Come to talk to you about the latest academic research and scientific development
最新の学術研究や科学の発展についてお話しましょう
Today I am very happy and honored to invite a researcher from the China Wen Zhe Institute of our school
本日は、本校の中国文哲研究院から研究員をお招きできることを大変うれしく光栄に思います。
Come to talk with you about China's first vernacular Bible
中国初の自国語聖書について話しましょう
From the seventh ninth year to the eighth year
7年目から8年目まで
Dr. Lee is a Master of English Literature from Commonwealth University
リー博士はコモンウェルス大学で英文学の修士号を取得しています。
PhD in Comparative Literature, University of Skagow
スカゴー大学比較文学博士号取得
Establishment Day Education Department of English, Soochow University Institute of Comparative Literature, Pujin University
設立日 教育 蘇州大学英語学科 プジン大学比較文学研究所
National Shiwan University English Institute and Translation Institute
国立師湾大学英語学院および翻訳学院
He is now a researcher at the Institute of Philosophy
彼は現在、文化哲学研究所の研究員です。
He is also a Professor of Peace at the Translation Institute of Normal University
彼は師範大学翻訳研究所の平和教授でもあります。
and agricultural researcher at the Translation Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong
香港中文大学翻訳センターの農業研究者
He is more familiar with engineering than Professor
彼は教授よりも工学に詳しい
so i shouldn't have read this
だからこれを読むべきではなかった
However, Professor Li has won many farmer awards including young assistants from our hospital.
しかし、李教授は当院の若手助手を含め、多くの農家賞を受賞しています。
Soochow University Outstanding Campus Tour Award
東州大学優秀キャンパスツアー賞
He just heard that he also gave lectures when he was competing for general universities and book schools
一般大学や書籍学校の受験時にも講義を行っていたと聞いた。
I lost to Cai Yinglin, so there is nothing wrong with this
蔡英林に負けたから何も問題ない
In 2010 and 2011, all translation research papers commemorative awards were sent
2010年と2011年にすべての翻訳研究論文記念賞を発送
and National Science Council and Book Research Award, etc.
国家学術会議および書籍研究賞など
Well, Professor Aristotle's education is rich
まあ、アリストテレス教授の教養は豊かだ
Know six or seven languages
6か7か国語を知っている
Then the writing waits for students
そして、執筆は生徒たちを待っています
Well, his works include Chinese and Western Civilization English People
さて、彼の作品には、中国と西洋文明、イギリス人が含まれます
Late Ming Dynasty in China to Middle Ages in Europe
中国明末からヨーロッパ中世
Qingming Jesuit Western Classical Administrative Road Story Exam
清明イエズス会西洋古典行政物語試験
Mingming Jesuits Translating Literature and Other Books
文学やその他の書籍を翻訳するイエズス会のミンミン
And he has translated a lot of books, I want to say that I don't mean to read them here
彼はたくさんの本を翻訳していますが、ここでそれらを読むつもりはないと言いたいのです。
But I recently saw a comment
でも、最近コメントを見たのですが、
I said, I can't see it, I just can see it
私は言った、私には見えない、ただ見えるだけだ
Then this comment thinks that he is the one who studies the translated literature of the late Ming Dynasty all over the world.
そして、このコメントは、彼が世界中の明代後期の翻訳文学を研究している人だと思います。
first person, then i'll paraphrase here
一人称、それではここで言い換えます
But he didn't get a chance to read this comment
しかし、彼はこのコメントを読む機会がありませんでした
So it can be seen that his translation in the late Ming Dynasty
したがって、明代後期の彼の翻訳は次のとおりであることがわかります。
So because the book will matter, this translation
この本は重要なので、この翻訳は
This history has a very important and authoritative position
この歴史は非常に重要かつ権威ある地位を占めています
do a lot of work on this
これにたくさんの仕事をしてください
including very detailed
非常に詳細な内容も含めて
Restrain this late Ming game-like translation of the classic
明末の古典のゲーム風の翻訳を抑制する
Although I still have to speak publicly
まだ公の場で話さなければならないのに
I advised him not to live so carefully
私は彼にあまり慎重に生きないように忠告した
I've been told this by him
彼からこう言われたことがあります
But these jobs are very big jobs
しかし、これらの仕事は非常に大きな仕事です
and it takes time
そして時間がかかります
This is the case in all aspects of knowledge and physical strength
知識も体力も全てにおいてそうです
Unprecedented 8 project investment
前例のない8プロジェクトへの投資
We also hope he gets these things done soon
私たちはまた、彼がこれらのことをすぐに完了することを願っています
Professor of Governance also served as Telephone Newspaper
ガバナンス教授は電話新聞も務めた
"China Times"
「チャイナタイムズ」
The Sino-British Daily has only Times columns and Su Ping writers
中英日報にはタイムズのコラムと蘇平の記者しか掲載されていない
So I guess his name is familiar to you all
彼の名前は皆さんにもよく知られていると思います
Although you still have to ask me at noon today
今日の昼にまだ頼まなければならないのに
Should I Study Liliology or Lishuangxue?
リリ学と李双学を勉強したほうがいいですか?
we are the word is very old
私たちはという言葉は非常に古いです
The word "Military" in the above book is the word
上記の本に出てくる「軍事」という言葉は、
so this
したがって、この
Today's speech is actually
実は今日のスピーチは、
You said it was mentioned in a small talk with me once
一度私との雑談の中でその話が出たと言っていましたね
I think this topic is very suitable
このテーマは非常に適切だと思います
I didn't expect to arrange the left arrangement and the right arrangement
左の配置と右の配置を並べるとは思わなかった
It's a coincidence that it's scheduled for Christmas today.
今日がクリスマスに予定されているのは偶然です。
this is totally unexpected
これはまったく予想外です
Because the small root of knowledge is Tuesday
小さな知識の根は火曜日だから
so tuesday
それで火曜日
Christmas
クリスマス
Attach your first "Vernacular Bible"
初めての「現地語聖書」を添付してください
it's a match made in heaven
それは天国で行われた試合です
We also give a big round of applause to welcome everyone
私たちも大きな拍手で皆様をお迎えいたします
Thank you Vice President Wang today
本日は王副社長に感謝します
I don't want to be sorry today
今日は謝りたくない
I compare why
なぜか比べてみた
I usually feel like I have a cold
普段は風邪を引いているような気がする
But it's stupid to talk about it
でもそれについて話すのは愚かだ
started yesterday
昨日から始まりました
Before I ask you, I figured it out myself
聞く前に自分で調べてみた
but say so
でもそう言ってください
He might be more magnetic
彼はもっと魅力的かもしれない
I have a self-deprecating place
私には自虐的なところがあります
what i'm going to talk about today
今日は何を話しますか
After the first "Vernacular Bible"
最初の「ヴァナキュラー聖書」の後
Is a Chinese Jesuit
中国のイエズス会士です
He Qingtai
何青台
OK He Jintao said he translated it
OK、何錦濤はそれを翻訳したと言いました
this is a very interesting person
この人はとても興味深い人です
I'll talk more about him later
彼については後で詳しく話します
before talking about him i think
彼のことを話す前に私は思う
The first of our Academia Sinica to come to Taiwan
中央研究院の初の台湾訪問
The first dean, Mr. Hu Shizhi
初代学部長胡世之氏
start from the beginning
最初から始める
OK Hu Shiyou is very respectful
OK、胡詩佑はとても敬意を持っています
At this time, this person who can step into the academic hall
このとき、学問の場に足を踏み入れられるこの人は、
Actually, I think personally
実は個人的に思うのですが、
The key is the influence of Hu Shi OK
鍵は胡石OKの影響
this Hushi
このフシ
I probably read Hu Shi's book when I was in high school
胡思の本を読んだのはおそらく高校生の頃
One of the things Hu Shi said in your book
胡思があなたの本の中で言ったことの一つ
recent in 50 years
50年ぶりの最新の
But it is spoken in English
でも英語で話されているので
OK
OK
So life in English is pushed back 50 years
英語での生活が50年延期される
The vernacular novel of this life is
この人生の日常的な小説は、
Vernacular literature in the past 1000 years
過去 1000 年間の郷土文学
has the same big drawback
同じ大きな欠点がある
That is to say, the adoption of vernacular
つまり、言語の採用
still meaningless
まだ無意味
meaningful
意味のある
doesn't make sense
意味がありません
in other words
言い換えると
if no english is spoken
英語が話せない場合
this story thinks before it
この物語はその前に考えます
This use of vernacular
この俗語の使用法
So
それで
is a
です
How to say
どのように言って
If it is not a product of the bookstore
書店の商品でない場合
then it is
それならそうです
Chat until there is no Jinshi
口コミが無くなるまでチャット 壬氏
or those who raise people
あるいは人を育てる人たち
the literati
文人
Then pick up the pen
それからペンを取りなさい
Initiate old income
古い収入を開始する
write a novel
小説を書く
OK
OK
this
これ
so is a
それもそうだ
unconsciously
無意識に
written in vernacular here
ここに現地語で書かれています
writing
書き込み
Hu Shi is greater than consciousness, probably like this
胡施は意識よりも偉大です、おそらくこんな感じです
so for him
だから彼にとって
these people
この人達
write this vernacular
この言葉を書いてください
neither
ない
conclusively in writing
最終的には書面で
ok
Ok
not conscious
意識がない
I want to create in vernacular
国語で作りたい
or to write
または書く
this
これ
i miss him
私は彼が恋しいです
he thought before
彼は前に思った
people are not like this
人はこんなものではない
but i personally
しかし私は個人的に
before
以前
did not touch this
これには触れませんでした
Mingjing
明静の機会
Before this work of the Society of Jesus
イエズス会のこの活動の前に
What is Hu Shi talking about?
胡施は何を話しているのでしょうか？
because he asks him again
彼がまた尋ねるので
I just want to ask him something
ただ彼に聞きたいことがあります
Later I realized that
後で気づいたのですが、
Hu Shi said this
胡施はこう言った
seems a little too much
少し多すぎるようです
a little too fast
少し速すぎる
ok
Ok
So I personally at this point in time
なので私個人としては現時点では
There are many things that are not necessarily their own
必ずしも自分のものではないものもたくさんあります
In fact, not yet
実際にはまだ
no one has seen it in a
誰もそれを見たことがありません
OK
OK
so
それで
This is also extenuating
これも酌量すべきです
OK
OK
The one about He Qiantai that I want to talk about today
今日話したいのは何銭台についてです
old and new bible
古くて新しい聖書
not such a book
そんな本ではない
so-called unintentional
いわゆる意図的でないもの
So-called
所謂的
this translated bible
翻訳された聖書
but
しかし
Intentional
意図的
use vernacular
現地の言葉を使う
to translate the bible
聖書を翻訳する
And this vernacular
そしてこの俗語
i don't know use this baby
この赤ちゃんを使っていいのか分からない
Although He Qiantai lives in Beijing
何銭台は北京に住んでいますが
OK
OK
he is
彼は
he is the jesuit history of france
彼はフランスのイエズス会の歴史です
but
しかし
he arrived when he was very young
彼はとても若いときにここに来た
this one
これです
Centaur
ケンタウロス
OK
OK
so he
彼は
he calls himself this
彼は自分のことをこう呼んでいます
Italian
イタリアの
is better than his this
彼のこれよりもいいです
How to say
どのように言って
here in french
ここはフランス語で
much better
ずっといい
OK
OK
When he came to China
彼が中国に来たとき
he put this
彼はこれを置きました
when he was first
彼が最初のとき
actually
実際
because we need to know something
私たちは何かを知る必要があるから
this china
この中国
in the qing dynasty
清の時代に
Mandarin
北京語
not us today
今日は私たちではありません
the so-called national language
いわゆる国語
ok or the so-called Beijing dialect in mainland China
OK、または中国本土のいわゆる北京語
The national language of the Qing Dynasty was Manchu
清朝の国語は満州語でした
ok is manchu
はい、満州です
When you come to China
中国に来たら
his first
彼の最初の
What about translating the above attempts
上記の試みを翻訳してみるとどうでしょうか
That's Manchu
それが満州族です
this attempt of the bible
聖書のこの試み
Then wait until he finishes the Manchu Bible
それから彼が読み終わった後に満州語の聖書を待ちます
he just started
彼は始めたばかりです
The nerve to do Chinese
中国語をやる度胸
ok
Ok
The Chinese nerve
中国人の神経
I don't think it's a
ではないと思います
How to say
どのように言って
commonly known as
一般にとして知られている
Beijing Guanhua
北京関華
ok a language like this
わかりました、このような言語です
i am not a linguist
私は言語学者ではありません
But I always feel that visualization is a class language
しかし、視覚化はクラス言語だといつも感じています
OK
OK
The one that talks about visualization
ビジュアライゼーションについて語るもの
you sooner or later
遅かれ早かれあなたは
You are even in the aspect of intonation
イントネーションの面でも
I'm afraid it's all
残念ですが、それだけです
must have that
それを持っているはずです
this kind of knowledge
この種の知識
a certain level of knowledge
一定レベルの知識
then he will speak
そうすれば彼は話すでしょう
OK
OK
Then even if you live in Beijing
それなら北京に住んでいても
You may not be talking about this so-called visualization
このいわゆる視覚化について話しているわけではないかもしれません。
but he was writing
しかし彼は書いていた
For example, when writing this Le Tuo box
たとえば、この楽佗ボックスを書いているとき
The so-called Beijing Tuyu
いわゆる北京トゥユ
OK
OK
Graphics are a little harder to hear
グラフィックが少し聞き取りにくい
Let's speak Beijing Shuyu
北京書遊を話しましょう
OK
OK
The Beijing Shuyu written by He Jinla
賀金拉著『北京書要』
when he writes well
彼が上手に書くとき
really great
ほんとうに素晴らしい
OK
OK
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
Let me check this one from He Jinla first.
まず、He Jinla のこれを確認しましょう。
this person is good
この人は良い人です
This He Jinla's
これはヘ・ジンラさんのもの
It is now China from 1770
1770年からは今は中国です
its actually a generation of jesuits
それは実際にはイエズス会の世代です
The end of the article is in Xinrong because
記事の最後は新栄です。
Its point in time is already
その時点はすでに
to this former farmer
この元農家に
If you count the first generation of Jesuits
イエズス会の初代を数えると
That should be counted immediately
それはすぐに数えるべきです
That was around 1588, 283
それは1588年、283年頃です。
Feature Master 1770's
フィーチャーマスター 1770年代
It's hundreds of years away from this
それから何百年も先の話だ
ok
Ok
so in the middle
だから真ん中に
In fact, China has gone through that kind of
実際、中国はそのような経験をしています
religious tolerance
宗教的寛容
Then next to bondage religion
次は束縛宗教です
ok
Ok
Then just ban you Catholic
それならカトリック教徒を追放すればいい
this one goes into china
これは中国に行きます
ok
Ok
that but
それはしかし
Although it says access to prohibit this
これを禁止するアクセスと書いてありますが、
Off home is forbidden
外出禁止
Catholicism enters China
カトリックが中国に進出
But the Catholic Church is telling the truth
しかしカトリック教会は真実を語っています
did not die
死ななかった
He became an underground frontrunner
彼はアンダーグラウンドのフロントランナーとなった
He's very active underground
彼は地下でとても活発に活動している
Thousand yuan is to drive out some missionaries
宣教師数名を追い出すには千元が必要
but then again
でもまたまた
If your calendar is very good
あなたのカレンダーがとても良いものであれば
very good at math
数学がとても得意です
very good legislation
とても良い法律
astronomy is very good
天文学はとても良いです
Shenzhen understands painting
深センは絵画を理解しています
Even if these people are the most severe warriors
たとえこの人たちが最も厳しい戦士だとしても
He also let them stay in this coffin
彼はまた彼らをこの棺に入れさせた
So in the coffin forest
だから棺の森で
I raised a group of so-called generals from the West
私は西洋からのいわゆる将軍のグループを育てました
or painter
または画家
you drink brilliantly
あなたは見事に飲みます
when you come to china
中国に来るとき
He probably never thought that he would be a flower stand
まさか自分がフラワースタンドになるとは思ってもいなかっただろう
just because he's a little
彼は小さいから
this talent in painting
この絵の才能
OK not a little big
OK、少し大きくない
talent for painting
絵を描く才能
So when he arrived in Beijing, people asked him what he was doing
それで彼が北京に到着したとき、人々は彼に何をしているのかと尋ねました
He made this one Latin very well
彼はこれをラテン語でとてもうまく作りました
OK
OK
Then China with this one
じゃあ中国もこれで
There is often that kind of border diplomacy with Russia
ロシアとはそういう国境外交がよくある。
trade or
貿易したり、
Even the question of national borders
国境の問題さえも
So he often intervenes in this Secondary School
それで彼はこの中学校に頻繁に介入します
this
これ
trade or
貿易したり、
some political issues
いくつかの政治的問題
translated a lot of this
これの多くを翻訳しました
something specialized becomes latin
特殊なものがラテン語になる
show this two
これを２つ見せて
OK
OK
Of course I don't know how his biography is.
もちろん彼の経歴がどうなっているのかは知りません。
but
しかし
once wanted to join
一度は参加したいと思っていた
Russian Jesuits
ロシアのイエズス会士
OK
OK
that anyway
それはともかく
let's answer him
彼に答えてみましょう
His identity as a chemist
化学者としての彼のアイデンティティ
He is the descendant of the so-called Hercynian faction
彼はいわゆる千キロメートルのヘルシニア学派の子孫です。
a hercynian is actually a
ヘルシニアンは実際には
Haixi is from the west
海西は西から来ました
The west of the sea is here
西の海はここにある
In fact, it was Wolf Shilin who shouted it out.
実際、それを叫んだのはウルフ・シーリンでした。
Or because of Wolf Shilin when they were talking
あるいは、彼らが話しているときのウルフ・シーリンのせいでしょうか
The inscription is Hercynian wolf-style forest
碑文はヘルシニアの狼風の森林
So there was such a so-called Hercynian
それで、そのようないわゆるヘルシニア人がいました
He Jintai is the last member of this faction.
何金台はこの派閥の最後のメンバーです。
When they came to China in 1776
1776年に彼らが中国に来たとき
Wolf Forest has been lost for five years
オオカミの森は5年間失われていた
So He Jintai has never seen this wolf-style forest
つまり、何錦台はこの狼のような森を見たことがありません
But He Jintai
しかし、ヘ・ジンタイ
Earlier, Wang Licheng asked He Jintai and said
以前、王立成は何錦泰に尋ねてこう言いました。
You go to imitate this wolf forest or something
このオオカミの森の真似をしに行くか何か
include this one
これを含めてください
Bai Juntu
バイ・ジュントゥ
Bai Juntu also sent
Bai Juntuも送った
make this
これ作って
have voted
投票しました
including Bai Juntu
バイ・ジュントゥを含む
He Juntu is more than you
彼はあなたよりも優れています
so
それで
He Juntu is thousands of kilometers away
何君図は何千キロも離れています
calculate
計算する
If you want to compare with Wang Shilin
王士林と比較するなら
he's not first class
彼はファーストクラスではない
Huajia
華佳
not much sister in law
義理の妹はあまりいない
also for this
これのためにも
how do you say
どのように言いますか
one in court
法廷での一人
Emphasis on location
所重視
one of Hu Jintao's
胡錦濤の一人
he wrote a book called
彼はという本を書きました
Picture Record of the Imperial Court
國朝院畫錄
He Jintai
何ジンタイ
Donglin Mao
毛東林
That is to say, he is good at drawing
つまり彼は絵が上手だ
this painted bird
このペイントされた鳥
OK to draw a bird
鳥を描いてもOK
what bird
何の鳥
I didn't understand the nouns
名詞が分かりませんでした
called Haiqing
海清と呼ばれる
blue is the love of blue sky
ブルーは青空の愛
OK
OK
Later, the seascape paper used to look up the dictionary was old silver or something like that.
その後、辞書を引くときに使った海景紙は古い銀色か何かでした。
So I showed a picture of this one
そこでこの写真を見せました
Lao Yin painted by He Jintai is over there
何金台が描いた老陰があそこにあります
Except for this old silver
この古い銀を除いて
He Jintai actually painted many other things
何金台は実際には他にもたくさんの作品を描きました
In addition, I found another record of this painting by him.
さらに、私は彼のこの絵に関する別の記録を見つけました。
we can see
見える
In fact, in a certain sense of the Hercynian school
実際、ある意味でのヘルシニアニズム
It is a combination of Chinese painting and Western painting
中国絵画と西洋絵画を組み合わせた作品です
I am not an art history researcher
私は美術史の研究者ではありません
That's probably all we're talking about
おそらく私たちが話しているのはそれだけです
I also know He Jin
私もヘ・ジンを知っています
did you say we must be free
私たちは自由でなければならないと言いましたか
Words from Gu Gong Museum Area
古公博物館エリアからの言葉
Mr. Gu's office and Father Wu
顧氏のオフィスと呉氏
Our Taipei Gugong
私たちの台北古功
I don't know Mr. Gu in mainland China
中国本土では谷さんを知りません
He has a martial father to Mr. Gu
谷氏には軍人の父親がいる
This painting by He Jintai
この絵は何金泰によるものです
So He Jintai
ソ・ヘ・ジンタイ
as the artist
アーティストとして
In the Qing Palace, the interaction with the emperor is relatively large
清の宮殿では皇帝との交流が比較的多い
OK
OK
that in private
それはプライベートで
sorry
ごめん
Another concern is the translation
もう一つの懸念は翻訳です
during diplomatic translation
外交翻訳中
he is always doing one thing
彼はいつも一つのことをしている
OK
OK
private translation
私的翻訳
Of course it's to fuck them
もちろん、それは彼らをファックするためです
sorry
ごめん
do their own bible translations
自分たちで聖書翻訳をする
i just said
私はちょうど言いました
This Manchu is the national language of the Qing Dynasty
この満州語は清朝の国語です
so
それで
this He Jintai
この何金台
Of course it's drawn from 1770
もちろん1770年に描かれたものです
After painting in 1770
1770 年に絵を描いた後
he started this bible
彼はこの聖書を書き始めました
you can change it
変更できます
That's not it
それではない
no
いいえ
There is a Date
日付があります
Ok,Date
わかりました、日付
Ok
Ok
he probably
彼はおそらく
Come to China in 1770 I think
1770年に中国に来たと思います
He has to learn Manchu
彼は満州語を学ばなければなりません
Ok, so it's probably impossible to say
わかりました、だから言うのはおそらく不可能です
Since 1770
1770年以来
This translation, this Manchu Bible
この翻訳、この満州聖書
Ok
Ok
but for some
しかし一部の人にとっては
words spoken by a language genius
語学の天才が語る言葉
I think
私が思うに
Well
良い
It is also difficult for us to say that he cannot be within three to five years
また、彼が3～5年以内に復帰できないとは言い難い。
uh at least after some degree of this manchu
ああ、少なくともこの満州をある程度終えた後は
Manchu in all aspects should be a kind of
満州語はあらゆる面で一種のものでなければなりません
flat phonetic characters, i don't understand
平仮名、分かりません
Ok, but I just because he should be a
わかりました、でも私は彼がそうであるべきだからです
Plain letters
平音文字
So under this Chinese
したがって、この中国語の下では
Well
良い
This country and scriptures from flat-yin script
この国と平陰文字の経典
probably for Manchu
おそらく満州人向け
should be
あるべきです
It is also easier to enter the situation
状況にも入りやすくなります
OK
OK
so
それで
this
これ
when did he start translating manchu
彼はいつ満州語の翻訳を始めましたか
We don't know about the bible
私たちは聖書のことを知りません
so full bible
とても完全な聖書
manuscript now
現在手稿
not herbal
ハーブではない
manuscript
原稿
It's in Japan's Toyo Bunko
日本の東洋文庫にあります
I don't know why and where I went
なぜどこへ行ったのか分かりません
OK
OK
Then the Japanese Toyo Bunko
それから日本の東洋文庫
The title given is called
付けられたタイトルはこう呼ばれます
Manchu complex
満州族コンプレックス
new covenant victory book
新就約勝書
I want to say that you will not belong to He Jintao
あなたは何錦濤に属さないと言いたい
his title
彼の称号
OK
OK
I don't know what happened to his title
彼のタイトルがどうなったのかは知りません
Completed this Manchu Bible in 1790
1790年にこの満州聖書を完成させた
This is certain because
これは確かなことだから、
He Jin has a friend
ヘ・ジンには友達がいます
This once wrote a letter saying
この人はかつてこう言う手紙を書きました
In 1790, He Jindai completed the translation of the Manchu Bible
1790年、何神代は満州語聖書の翻訳を完成させた
OK
OK
so it's very, very clear
それはとてもとても明らかです
You have to wait until the translation of the Manchu scriptures is finished
満州経典の翻訳が終わるまで待たなければなりません
You put the most important thing in the Qing Dynasty
清朝で最も重要なものを置きました
That is to say, the most important thing for Qing people is Manchu
つまり、清人にとって最も重要なものは満州族であるということです。
after you've done it
それをやった後
You might just say come back
戻って来いと言うかもしれない
How do you say this
どのようにこれを言うのですか
to deal with this
これに対処するために
In fact, there are many more Han Chinese than Manchurians
実際、満州人よりも漢民族の方がはるかに多い
OK
OK
so
それで
The earliest he could have been in the 1790s
彼がいたのは最も早くても 1790 年代だったはず
early 1790
1790年初
or 1790
または1790年
He can start translating
彼は翻訳を始めることができます
this
これ
this nerve in Chinese
この神経中国語の意味
OK
OK
So
それで
very interesting
とても興味深い
exist
存在
This horse bean of the New Testament
新約聖書のこの馬豆
Wanyue Green means Gospel
ワンユエグリーンは福音を意味します
this
これ
this saint
この聖人
holy
聖
I don't think so
私はそうは思わない
i say
私は言う
San Matthew
マシューのように
OK
OK
It is the Gospel of Madou
それはマドゥの福音です
When he was translating a gospel of horse beans
彼が馬豆の福音書を翻訳していたとき
has a comment
コメントがあります
write to say
言うために書く
Dokei
道敬
this i think
これは私が思う
Impossible 1800 Daoist
インポッシブル1800トリビュート
this should be in the middle
これは真ん中にあるはずです
he is missing a word
彼は言葉が足りない
or super person this
または超人これ
one word missing
一言足りない
It should be one hundred and eighteen hundred years ago
百一千八百年前のはずだ
Dokei
道敬
OK
OK
so
それで
this
これ
We can probably imagine that
おそらくそれは想像できるでしょう
this He Jintai
この何金台
should be
あるべきです
in the 19th century
19世紀に
this one
これです
that one
それです
The moment the eighteenth turned to the nineteenth century
18世紀から19世紀に変わる瞬間
OK
OK
he officially translated
彼は正式に翻訳した
this new music
この新しい音楽
OK
OK
what about old music
古い音楽はどうですか
I started translating a long time ago
私はずっと前に翻訳を始めました
He flipped a lot of this old music
彼は古い音楽をたくさんひっくり返した
OK
OK
text also disappeared
文字も消えた
Well said
よく言った
In total he actually translated
合計すると、彼は実際に翻訳しました
If according to this Chinese volume
この中国語の本によると
how to say this word
この言葉をどう言うか
He translated a total of 36 volumes
合計36巻を翻訳した
But what about the 36 volumes
でも36巻はどうなるの？
This roll cannot be brought
このロールは持ち込めません
the book of the bible
聖書の本
Equal and close
同等で近い
Because if the word in the Bible is written in English
なぜなら、聖書の言葉が英語で書かれているとしたら、
It's called Bokeh
それをボケといいます
Libbe in Latin
ラテン語で「リッベ」
so
それで
36 Chinese Rolls by He Jintao
何錦濤の中華ロール 36 個
is equal to this western bible
この西洋の聖書に等しい
About 56, 7 Bokeh
56、7ボケ程度
ok
Ok
this
これ
talking about being catholic
カトリックであることについて話す
I'm sure you must know that
きっとあなたもそれを知っているはずです
catholic this one
カトリックのこれ
as far as
の限り
what you believe
あなたが信じていること
this one
これです
The so-called homeless big bible
いわゆるホームレスの大バイブル
OK Homeless Large Bible
OK ホームレス大聖書
What about the Big Homeless Bible?
ホームレス大聖書はどうでしょうか？
It's very different from this Protestant Bible.
このプロテスタントの聖書とは大きく異なります。
OK
OK
The Big Homeless Bible has 73 volumes in total
ホームレス大聖書は全部で 73 巻あります
So he translated 567 volumes
それで彼は567冊を翻訳しました
These 36 volumes are equal to 567 volumes
この36巻は567巻に相当します。
Homeless Big Book, this Bible
ホームレスビッグブック、この聖書
In fact, only a small part remains
実はほんの一部しか残っていない
This one didn't turn over
こっちはひっくり返らなかった
OK
OK
He is not only in a translation of the bible
彼は聖書の翻訳だけではありません
He also commented on the Bible
彼は聖書についてもコメントしました
OK Commentary Bible
OK 解説聖書
so
それで
Inside the 36 volumes
36巻の中身
36 volumes
36巻
When I go to the academic association, I often say that when I go to see this one.
学会に行くと、これを見に行くとよく言います。
I found it was volume 36
調べたら36巻だった
uh how to say we come back
ああ、戻ってくるって何て言うの？
do the math
計算する
More than 1.5 million words
150万語以上
OK
OK
how many money
何金貸
When this agent completes this is at least 36 rolls
このエージェントが完了すると、少なくとも 36 ロールになります
OK, it is still a difficult time to scrutinize
OK、まだ精査するのは難しい時期です
about the only way we can say
私たちが言える唯一の方法について
make a little guess
少し推測してください
Probably around 1805
おそらく1805年頃
why i say 1805
なぜ私が1805年と言うのか
because in 1803
なぜなら1803年に
He Jinnai once wrote a letter to the Holy See, but the letter did not go
賀陣内はかつて教皇庁に手紙を書いたが、その手紙は届かなかった
Catholicism is different from ordinary Christian denominations
カトリックは通常のキリスト教の宗派とは異なります
Catholicism is a centralized and large system
カトリックは中央集権的で大きなシステムです
You don't understand anything in theory
理論的には何も理解していない
I think I should get to the Holy See
ローマ教皇庁に行くべきだと思う
there is the Holy See
ローマ教皇庁がある
Especially when the pope decides to say
特に教皇がこう言うと決めたときは
can
可否
OK
OK
so
それで
He Jinnaita
ヘ・ジンナイタ
After reversing thirty-six volumes
36巻を裏返した後
he wrote
彼が書きました
in 1803
1803年に
He wrote to the Holy See
彼は教皇庁に手紙を書いた
explain
説明
Can I limit my subjects?
科目を制限することはできますか?
I dug it out now
今掘り出しました
Thirty-six volumes
三十六巻
OK
OK
He Jinnai is very
陣内さんはとても
I think he might be more
彼はもっといるかもしれないと思う
naive
ナイーブな
he should know
彼は知っているはずだ
The Magic Horse Church is actually
マジックホースチャーチは実際には
If i remember correctly
もし私が正確に覚えていれば
around 1612
1612年頃
OK
OK
the pope
法王
just ban
ただ禁止するだけ
This is in various dialects
これはいろいろな方言で
That is to say, the national languages ​​of various countries
つまり、各国の国語
to translate this nerve
この神経を翻訳する
only one nerve
神経は一本だけ
Not Hebrew
ヘブライ語ではありません
Nor is it Greek
ギリシャでもない
OK is Latin
OKはラテン語です
So why did He Jinnai not gamble?
では、なぜヘ・ジンナイはギャンブルをしなかったのでしょうか？
That is to say no gambling in the ban of 1612
つまり、1612年にはギャンブルは禁止されなかったということです。
This he went to China
この人は中国に行きました
he translates nerves over there
彼はそこの神経を翻訳します
this is an interesting question
これは興味深い質問です
But I can't give you an answer
でも答えられないよ
I can only say that He Jinnai's first one might be a little too naive
ヘ・ジンナイの最初のものは少し単純すぎるかもしれないとしか言​​えません
Because the Holy See has lifted the ban
ローマ教皇庁が禁止令を解除したから
Because it's been a long time
久しぶりだから
Now it makes sense to think so.
今ではそう考えるのも当然です。
Because the few Western missionaries who were in Beijing at that time
なぜなら、当時北京にいた西洋人宣教師は数人しかいなかったからです。
In fact, they are under strict supervision.
実際、彼らは厳しい監視下にあります。
OK
OK
you can't talk nonsense
ナンセンスなことを話してはいけません
You can only go to and from get off work every day
毎日仕事の行き帰りしかできない
get off work
仕事を辞める
ok you are a painter
わかりました、あなたは画家です
ok, then you go to this Ruyi Pavilion in Yueming Garden every day
はい、それでは岳明園にある如懿閣に毎日行ってください。
to draw
描く
What about painting culture?
絵画文化についてはどうですか？
you should go home
あなたは家に帰ったほうがいいです
ok then you want this one to write back to this one's home country
わかりました。では、この人にこの人の母国に返事を書いてもらいたいのですが
ok your family and so on
オーケー、あなたの家族など
you can't say like we write now
私たちが今書いているようなことは言えません
Write something and I will lose this mailbox
何か書くとこのメールボックスが失われるよ
ok no such thing
わかりました、そんなことはありません
ok, you have to send it to a unit of the Ministry of Internal Affairs
わかりました、総務省の部署に送らなければなりません
There's nothing wrong with checking from there
そこから確認すれば問題ありません
ok of course
もちろんです
uh you didn't write this one
ああ、これはあなたが書いたものではありません
say now
今言ってください
uh its italian better than french
ああ、フランス語よりイタリア語のほうがいいよ
ok if you want to write in italian
イタリア語で書きたいならOK
probably no one over there will be able to check his italian
おそらく向こうでは彼のイタリア語を確認できる人は誰もいないだろう
Uh, but maybe go to another Jesuit
ああ、でも別のイエズス会に行くかもしれない
What does it mean
どういう意味ですか
say something in it
その中で何かを言う
ok finished speaking, if there is no problem
OK、話し終えました、問題なければ
Oh, let this letter go
ああ、この手紙は手放しましょう
You can go back to this Italian area
このイタリアエリアに戻れます
In this situation, if you think about it
この状況でよく考えてみると
How many letters can he write in English?
彼は英語で何文字書けますか?
Each letter is covered by this party membership
各手紙はこの党員の対象となります
or every letter is checked
またはすべての文字がチェックされます
His English is actually very limited.
彼の英語は実際には非常に限られています。
Once, once, there was a man named Detianshi
むかしむかし、徳天師という男がいました。
A Catholic missionary who forgot his nationality
国籍を忘れたカトリック宣教師
He has not been taught
彼は教えられていない
Sorry, this clear procedure
申し訳ありませんが、この明確な手順は
he took this one
彼はこれを持って行きました
This letter from several missionaries
数人の宣教師からのこの手紙
I want to say, OK, I will entrust another Chinese
いいよ、もう一人の中国人を任せるよと言いたい
Because he is going to the EU
彼はEUに行く予定なので
OK, I will entrust him, when this one goes to the EU
分かった、この人がEUに行くときは彼に任せるよ
By the way, please send me this letter from the European Union.
ところで、欧州連合からこの手紙を送ってください。
send it, all right
送ってください、わかりました
This becomes a Jia Qingxiang
これは賈清祥になります
the very famous Detus case
非常に有名なデトゥス事件
OK
OK
Detianshi did it because of this
徳天師はこのためにやった
he was old
彼は年をとっていた
OK
OK
sent this heat
この熱を送った
Go to the South China Sea to share hardships
南シナ海へ行き苦難を分かち合う
It took five or six years to return to Beijing
北京に戻るまで5、6年かかった
So they were
彼らはそうでした
in Beijing
北京で
Although it is said that East, West, North and South Church
東西南北教会と言われていますが、
But this kind of connection with the Holy See
しかし、この種の教皇庁とのつながりは、
Actually not very strong
実はあまり強くない
So I miss Mrs. He Jin
だからヘジンさんがいなくて寂しいです
she doesn't know
彼女は知りません
For example, the Holy See is
たとえば、ローマ教皇庁は、
Unban or not yet
禁止を解除するか、まだしていないか
she is in beijing anyway
とにかく彼女は北京にいる
she's fine
彼女は元気だ
She came home after painting
彼女は絵を描いてから帰ってきた
except for a prayer
祈りを除いて
I'll just be there the rest of the time
残りの時間はただそこにいるよ
How to say
どのように言って
over there this translation
あそこにこの翻訳があります
Bible
聖書
This must also be correct
これも正しいはずです
a very
とても
a wrong concept
間違った概念
I just say
私はちょうど言います
the old missionary
古い宣教師
It doesn't seem to translate this nerve
この神経は伝わらないようだ
OK Protestants don’t understand this old religion very much.
OK、プロテスタントはこの古い宗教を理解していません
OK, many scholars actually meet the requirements
OK、多くの学者は実際に要件を満たしています
This Protestant saying
プロテスタントのこの格言
OK I want to look at it from an academic point of view
はい、学術的な観点から見ていきたいと思います
Guxin's nerves came out today
今日はGuxinの神経が浮き出た
We should say there is nothing wrong old teacher
老先生は何も悪くないと言うべきだ
Of course, this nerve has not been given rights and interests to complete
もちろん、この神経には完了するための権利や利益が与えられていません。
But someone from the old teacher had that motive
でも昔の先生の誰かがそういう動機を持っていたんだ
have that attempt
その試みをしてください
OK have that attempt
OK、やってみます
he wants rights
彼は権利を望んでいる
This martial arts Osaka this nerve
この格闘技大阪この神経
this nerve of their belief
彼らの信念のこの神経
ok so i figured this out
わかりました、それで私はこれを理解しました
possible
可能
The neuroresearch community
神経研究コミュニティ
I need to go to the hearing for a while
しばらく傍聴に行かなければなりません
the old idea
古い考え
OK
OK
just mentioned that is to say
先ほど言いました、つまり
because I really don't know
本当にわからないから
hello christmas when is this
こんにちは、クリスマス、いつですか
How can I say it? It's hard to understand.
なんというか、わかりにくいですね。
OK
OK
I can probably only speculate that
おそらくそれは推測することしかできません
He sent this letter in 1803
彼は 1803 年にこの手紙を送りました
With the traffic conditions at that time
その時の交通事情により
In 1803, there were no booster ships
1803 年にはブースター船は存在しませんでした
OK
OK
The booster ship may have come around 1820
ブースター船は1820年頃に登場した可能性がある
so he should be
だから彼はそうあるべきだ
It should be this general this
これは一般的にこれであるべきです
normal ship
通常の船
OK
OK
That
それか
this letter
この手紙
To pray from this pan-terrestrial tank of this Chinese offering
この中国の製品の汎陸生水槽から祈ること
In fact, I will calculate for him
実際、私が彼のために計算してみます
It should be at least two years
少なくとも2年はかかるはず
OK for two years
2年なら大丈夫
So even if he is 1805
つまり、たとえ彼が 1805 年であっても
OK
OK
36 donations for his pan-terrestrial tank
彼の汎陸生戦車に 36 件の寄付
but a little worried
でも少し心配
OK
OK
Give him another three years
彼にあと3年与えてください
so i this
だから私はこれ
I said lower limit
下限って言ったけど
maybe 1808
おそらく1808年
how can i say maybe
たぶんどう言えばいいでしょうか
to 1790
1790年まで
is almost a certain point in time
ほぼ特定の時点です
OK
OK
That's because
それは、
He is in this period
彼はこの時期にいる
In the past ten years
過去10年間で
He turned the whole date over.
彼は日付を全部ひっくり返した。
what about the new covenant
新しい契約はどうですか
In fact, most of them are translated
実際、ほとんどが翻訳されています
OK
OK
And the translation is quite interesting
そして翻訳もなかなか面白いです
i think we can take a look
見てみることができると思います
This picture of the new testament is good
新約聖書のこの絵は良いですね
OK
OK
This is what we call Genesis
これが私たちが創世記と呼ぶものです
what we call genesis today
今日私たちが創世記と呼ぶもの
the word creation
創造という言葉
I haven't done my research
私は自分の研究をしていない
but i'm going to answer
でも私は答えるつもりです
possibly from
おそらくから
Luewen turned around
ルーウェンは振り向いた
OK
OK
I don't know very well
よくわかりません
but
しかし
What about He Jintai?
何金台はどうですか？
I'm sure he's a bible
彼は聖書だと確信しています
someone who knows very well
とてもよく知っている人
because
なぜなら
Today's biblical studies
今日の聖書研究
research community
研究コミュニティ
often think that say ah
ああ言うとよく思います
this
これ
What about Genesis?
ジェネシスはどうですか？
There are actually two stories
本当は２つの話があるのですが、
pieced together
つなぎ合わせた
OK
OK
That
それか
What about He Jintai?
何金台はどうですか？
he put this
彼はこれを置きました
This Genesis
この創世記
He is a brave protector
彼は勇敢な守護者だ
honestly
本音
his genesis he divided
彼の起源を彼は分けた
one knife two paragraphs
ナイフ1本、2段落
just cut in two
ただ二つに切るだけ
two
二
two volumes
2巻
OK
OK
god made man
神が人間を作った
everything else
ほかのすべて
He is called the gene of formation
彼は形成の遺伝子と呼ばれています
OK
OK
Of course it turns into these two words
もちろんこの2つの言葉になります
turned into heaven and earth
天と地に変わった
This saying should come from the Yijing
このことわざは易経から来ているはずです
Painted as heaven and earth or waist
天と地または腰として描かれています
this one from over there
これはあそこから
After this human being begins to recover
この後人類は回復し始めます
Create a variety of different carriages
さまざまな馬車を作成する
utensils
食器
etc
等
Then this face-changing of human beings themselves
そして、この人間自身の顔の変化
Abraham's fingering and all that stuff
エイブラハムの運指とかその他諸々
what about that part
その部分はどうですか
It's called the Sutra of Creation
それは創生経典と呼ばれています
OK
OK
So in a sense
だからある意味では
I miss He Jinnai
ヘ・ジンナイが懐かしい
He Jinnai is more sensitive
陣内はもっと敏感だよ
Actually cut the bible like this
実際に聖書をこのように切り取る
I don't believe it after that
その後は信じられない
If he said that the preaching of the Roman Way
もし彼がローマ法の説教だと言うならば、
This copy of an Old New Bible
この新旧聖書のコピー
If there are people who know Chinese in the Roman Road
ローマ街道に中国語わかる人がいたら
I can't believe this one they will unify
これで統一するなんて信じられない
This publication of this book
この本の出版にあたり、
OK
OK
He still burns him out
彼はまだ燃え尽きてしまう
no matter what
何があっても
we see
私たちは見る
He Jindai
何神代
he this
彼はこれ
new moon night
新月の夜
Employment? It's about the same.
雇用?ほぼ同じです。
then this is
それならこれは
We are all familiar
私たちは皆よく知っています
So I edited this picture out
そこでこの写真を編集してみました
you can see
見ることができます
this
これ
at first
初めに
At first it was
最初はそうでした
From martial arts to heaven and earth
武道から天地へ
Then the earth is empty and bare
そのとき地球は空っぽで何もない
dark shadow
暗い影
on extremely deep surface
非常に深い表面に
Holy Spirit
聖霊
walking on water
水の上を歩く
this i think
これは私が思う
If there are Christians doing this again
もしまた同じことをするキリスト教徒がいたら
to this
これに
This paragraph should be
この段落は次のようにする必要があります
more familiar than me
私よりも詳しい
OK
OK
Fighting dead is the Latin Deus
死者との戦いはラテン語のデウス
In fact, it is the consciousness of God
実はそれは神の意識なのです
that's actually
それは実際に
Nemesis generation this era
この時代のネメシス世代
He is actually not supposed to use Shake Corpse
彼は実際にはシェイクコープスを使用することになっていません
he used god
彼は神を利用した
He should have used the word God
彼は神という言葉を使うべきだった
OK
OK
Because it was still in the Ming Dynasty in 1627
1627年はまだ明の時代だったから
in 1627
1627年
this
これ
Some of the larger
より大きなもののうちのいくつかは、
The more important one is the Jesuit
もっと重要なのはイエズス会です
For example, like Long Huangping
たとえば、龍黄平のように
high character
高一字
Jin Yige wait for these Jesuits
ジン・イーゲはイエズス会士たちを待っています
When they were in 1627
彼らが1627年にいた頃
they are in the family this one
彼らはこの家族の一員です
Shanghai
上海
Shanghai family place
上海の家族の場所
where they meet
彼らが出会う場所
11 Jesuits
11 イエズス会
in 1627
1627年
Xu Guang's early days
徐広の初期の頃
Yang Tingwen, they are still there
ヤン・ティンウェン、彼らはまだそこにいる
they also practice
彼らも練習します
give opinions
意見を言う
they debate over there
彼らはそこで議論します
OK
OK
What are you arguing about?
何について議論しているのですか？
OK, low big evil
OK、低大悪
How exactly should I translate
具体的にはどのように訳せばいいのでしょうか
OK, how to translate
さて、どうやって翻訳するか
Are you going to translate to this one
これに翻訳するつもりですか
Well
良い
uh god
ああ、神様
or translated as God
または神と訳される
OK, uh, or translated into
OK、ええと、または翻訳すると
uh, you just use
ああ、あなたはただ使うだけです
English translation
英訳
are you calling it
あなたはそれを呼んでいますか
Doos and Fighters
ドゥースとファイターズ
English is similar, or you want
英語も似ているか、欲しい
Hurry up and call Doos
急いでドゥースに電話してください
OK, uh, I want
わかりました、ああ、欲しいです
anyway, uh
とにかく、ああ
this one two thousand years
これは二千年後
These people reached the final conclusion
この人たちは最終的な結論に達しました
yes
はい
uh, this, they have been
ああ、これ、彼らはそうだった
win, ok, that is to say
勝て、分かった、つまり
uh, they think this
ああ、彼らはこう考えている
Doos should be translated as God
ドゥースは神と訳すべき
OK, that
わかりました、それは
What about Luo Wenning's faction?
羅文寧派はどうなる？
It was a failure because Luo Wenning
羅文寧は失敗だった
This pie, then I am Chinese
このパイなら私は中国人だ
There is no equivalent to this Doos at all
この Doos に相当するものはありません
this concept of this
このコンセプト
uh uh
ああ、ああ
name
名前
So Meng Wanping insisted that
そこで孟晩平はこう主張した。
Since there is no
無いので
Then it should be translated in a responsive way
次に、応答性の高い方法で翻訳する必要があります
OK
OK
It's just that Meng Wanping doesn't
孟晩平はそうではないだけです
did not succeed
成功しませんでした
this He Jintai
この何金台
possible
可能
when he translated
彼が翻訳したとき
Maybe he has his own considerations
もしかしたら彼にも彼なりの考えがあるのか​​もしれない
OK
OK
When he translated this Deus
彼がこのデウスを翻訳したとき
he always
彼はいつも
still
まだ
He followed Meng Wanping
彼は孟望平をフォローした
He translates as a Deus
彼はデウスとして翻訳されます
Translated into a Dou Shi Dou Sister
Dou Shi Dou Sisterに翻訳されました
only when encountering some
何かに遭遇したときだけ
When not the word Deus
デウスという言葉が通じないときは
He will switch to other usage
彼は他の用途に切り替えるでしょう
for example
例えば
Deus
神
The word Deus
デウスという言葉
Dominus
マスター
In fact, it is the consciousness of the Lord
実はそれは主の意識なのです
ok main
OK 主
the Lord
ザ・ロード
the master
マスター
How am I aware?
どうして私は気づいているのでしょうか？
Like Dominionist, he turned it into this group
ドミニオニストのように、彼はそれをこのグループに変えました
Sometimes he is different into the upper group
時々彼は上のグループとは違う
this
これ
he is all we know
私たちが知っているのは彼だけです
Until now
今まで
first discussed in China
中国で最初に議論された
This so-called Teachable Grammation
このいわゆる Teachable Grammation
the first person with a so-called very good question
いわゆる非常に良い質問をした最初の人
Although it is said that Mohangnian had already started to debate in 1627
モハンニアンは1627年にはすでに議論を始めていたと言われているが、
But this person who will discuss all the holy names
しかしこの人はすべての聖なる名前について議論するだろう
is the core station
基幹局です
he even
彼さえも
I don't like the ones in the middle
真ん中の人は好きじゃない
He's even in one of his teaching assistants for the Paleo Bible
彼はパレオ聖書のティーチングアシスタントの一人でもある
He said
彼は言った
this
これ
this Java
このジャワ
Whether you can still fire in a night
一晩でも発砲できるかどうか
Or modern people change their name to Yahweh
あるいは現代人は名前をヤハウェに変える
He Jin told you
ヘ・ジンがあなたに言いました
This Dos warrior has no tacit understanding of this name
このドス戦士はこの名前を暗黙の了解としていない
In fact, the name is from the 16th century.
実はこの名前は16世紀に遡ります。
just synthesized a name
名前を合成しただけです
Protestants have been using this name
プロテスタントはこの名前を使用しています
so you're in the old bible
つまり、あなたは古い聖書の中にいるのです
The name Jehovah cannot be found
ヤハウェという名前は見つからない
He Jin did a lot of this type of work anyway
何進はとにかくこの種の仕事をたくさんしました
So I said that within 1.5 million words
だから私は150万語以内でそう言いました
About a quarter of them are annotations
そのうち約 4 分の 1 は注釈です
This quarter of the note is very important
メモのこの 4 分の 1 は非常に重要です
Because after China succeeded Yang Maluo
中国が楊マルオを引き継いだ後だから
Yang Marlowe's Straightforward Explanation of the Bible
ヤン・マーロウの率直な聖書解説
that is not a complete bible
それは完全な聖書ではありません
that's part of the bible
それは聖書の一部です
Bible Straightforward
聖書をわかりやすく
After that, in a very large Bible
その後、非常に大きな聖書で
Refer to a book with a lot of annotations
注釈がたくさんある本を参照する
So I think this is
だからこれはそうだと思う
if i'm free that day
その日空いていれば
I want to write an article called "He Jintai's Theory of Lifting the Ban"
「何金台の解禁論」という記事を書きたいと思っています。
because I feel that some places
場所によってはそう感じるから
He Jintai may have told them the interpretation of the Church of Rome
何晋台は彼らにローマ教会の解釈を語った可能性がある
there is some distance
ある程度の距離があります
he has his own opinion
彼は自分の意見を持っている
Let alone coming to China
中国に来るどころか
It's unlikely that you don't have your own opinion.
あなたが自分の意見を持っていない可能性は低いです。
That text by He Jintai
那賀金太的這個文字
what is it like
それはどんな感じですか
I think we'll look at this first
まずはこれを見てみようと思います
"Holy Mother Hopes for You" Mo Zhimeng is ready
「聖母はあなたを望んでいます」莫志夢は準備ができています
This is the preface of his "No Spirit Sutra"
これは彼の『無霊経』の序文です。
This is also the prologue
これもプロローグです
In total he wrote two parts of this preface to the Old and New Bibles
彼は新旧聖書の序文の合計 2 つの部分を書きました。
He even how the Bible should be typeset
彼は聖書がどのように植字されるべきかさえも教えてくれました
We call typesetting today
今日私たちは写植と呼んでいます
He made it very clear
彼はそれを非常に明確に言いました
you want to add one line you want to add two lines
1行追加したい場合 2行追加したい場合
you want a frame
フレームが欲しいですか
where to use small print
小さな文字をどこで使用するか
In fact, he made it very clear in his preamble.
実際、彼は前文でそれを明確に述べました。
But what?
でも何？
What I value most is the dream of St. Gerald and Ning Lonely
私が一番大切にしているのはセント・ジェラルドとニン・ロンリーの夢です
this place
この場所
St. Geraldine
セントジェラルディン
this may be unfamiliar
これは馴染みがないかもしれません
non-religious people wait
無宗教の人は待つ
Non-religious people should be familiar with a name called
無宗教の人は、という名前をよく知っているはずです。
Sanger Room
サンガールーム
holy
聖
Jer Room
ジャールーム
Anyway
ともかく
Shengre Luo Ning Lone is the Sanger Room
Shengre Luo Ning ローンはサンガールームです
Definitely this one of the five big bibles
間違いなくこれは五大聖書の一つです
How do you say this
どのようにこれを言うのですか
Interested person
興味のある方
ok
Ok
That Kowloon
あの九龍
this
これ
It is said
と言われています
That Kowloon is a very good Latin guy
九龍はとても優秀なラテン人だ
ok
Ok
That
それか
It is said that he
彼はそう言われています
When we start translating the Bible
聖書の翻訳を始めるとき
Well he is the same as this
まあ彼もこれと同じだ
a very beautiful this
とても美しいこれ
The problem with Cicero
シセロの問題
translate this bible
この聖書を翻訳してください
ok
Ok
That
それか
this bible
この聖書
Can you translate like this?
このように訳していただけますか？
this is a big problem
これは大きな問題です
I'll miss him later
後で彼がいなくなると寂しくなるよ
Then anyway when he translates like this
とにかく、彼がこのように翻訳すると、
How long has it been?
どのぐらいかかりましたか？
Eh
えー
we say so
私たちはそう言います
one day he was sleeping
ある日彼は眠っていた
ok
Ok
in sleep
睡眠中
god god nerve
神神神経
turned into an angel today
今日は天使になりました
just a few angels
ほんの数人の天使たち
that's a whip
それは鞭です
You guys still have mace
君たちはまだメイスを持っている
this philosophy
この哲学
then hit him
それから彼を殴る
Hit until you hit this mixed injury
この混合損傷を打つまで打ってください
While beating him, he laughed and said
彼を殴りながら、彼は笑ってこう言った。
You are the disciple of C15
あなたはC15の弟子です
we're here for the shit
私たちはたわごとのためにここにいます
come to get you
あなたを迎えに来てください
Just hit him with this
これで彼を殴ってください
as this bag
このバッグのように
nine people wake up
9人が目覚める
Of course it hurts to be beaten
もちろん殴られると痛いです
wake up soon
すぐに起きてください
after waking up
起きた後
Those Angels are gone
あの天使たちは去ってしまった
Nine is Saint
ナインは聖人です
saint
聖人
Catholic Fort the Saint
カトリックの聖者砦
translates to saint
聖人に訳される
saint he feels pain all over
聖人、彼は全身に痛みを感じています
Maybe he also finds himself mixed
もしかしたら彼も自分が複雑であることに気づいているかもしれない
there is that edge mark
そのエッジマークがあります
I fell out of bed wondering if he was sleeping
彼が寝ているのかと思ってベッドから落ちた
OK
OK
anyway
ともかく
all in all
概して
the whole long time
整個久遠
Only then did I realize that
そのとき初めて気づいたのですが、
oh
おお
this translated bible
この翻訳された聖書
I won't ask which kind of prettiest this one
これがどれが一番美しいかは聞きません
this problem
この問題
style
スタイル
or style
またはスタイル
OK
OK
to translate
翻訳すること
Of course there is a reason for this
もちろんこれには理由があります
OK
OK
Two appointments in the New Territories
新界での2つの予定
The interval of about 500 years in the middle
途中約500年の間隔
What about the Old Testament era?
旧約聖書の時代はどうでしょうか？
Actually most people
実はほとんどの人が
Don't say people like Jesus and others
人々はイエスやその他の人々のようなものだとは言わないでください
In fact, many people are shepherds.
実際、多くの人が羊飼いです。
OK
OK
shepherd you expect him this one
羊飼い、あなたは彼にこれを期待しています
including the heretics
異端者も含めて
OK
OK
How high do you expect him to be in this deal?
この契約で彼はどのくらいのレベルにいると予想しますか?
Then they are here all day and night
それから彼らは昼も夜もここにいます
There's one that's sloppy, etc.
ずさんなものなどあります。
OK Shepherd, boil water and grass but refuse
OK 羊飼い、水と草を沸かしてください、でも断ってください
OK, tell me how good this kind of education they can be
OK、この種の教育がどれだけ優れているのか教えてください
I think this is a big problem
これは大きな問題だと思う
OK so how to say
さて、どう言えばいいでしょうか
uh this
ああ、これ
So this is a date
だからこれはデートだよ
Just ask everyone not to think of it as saying
皆さんには、こう言っているとは思わないでください。
Of course, it is a question as great as our Fourteenth Five-Year Classics.
もちろん、これは第 14 回の 5 年間の古典と同じくらい素晴らしい問題です。
uh written stuff
ああ、書かれたもの
Then it's quite, uh, how to say this?
それから、それはかなり、えー、これをどう言うか？
The language of the book is quite reasonable.
この本の言語は非常に合理的です。
OK although I don't understand Hebrew
ヘブライ語はわかりませんが、わかりました
But to understand this uh
でもこれを理解するには
Just make an appointment, it is written in a language that is quite reasonable
予約するだけです。非常に合理的な言語で書かれています
except for the whole
全体を除いて
middle two exceptions
中2例外
San Yongji and this
サンヨンジとこれ
Uh, it's commonly known as locking our prince brother's
ああ、それは一般的に私たちの王子の兄弟をロックすることとして知られています
OK
OK
part of this thing
このことの一部
ok
Ok
that is poetry
それは詩です
of course it's impossible
もちろんそれは不可能です
Tata Tata
用太太太
too vulgar to write in this language
この言語で書くにはあまりにも下品すぎる
The others
他人
this is recommended
これはお勧めです
Wrong place to start
始める場所が間違っている
actually follow
実際にフォローする
not so
そうではありません
That is to say, the style is
つまりスタイルは
are all comparisons
すべては比較です
lower level
下位レベル
ok
Ok
and you
あなたも
think about it
考えてみてください
when jesus was twelve
イエスが12歳のとき
just come out and follow one
ただ出てきて一人に従ってください
At that time, there was this teacher of the Tairen
その時、大連の先生がいらっしゃいました。
debate over there in the temple
あそこの神殿で議論する
ok
Ok
a twelve year old boy
12歳の男の子
how smart is jesus
イエスはどれくらい賢いですか
Just think about a twelve year old kid
12歳の子供のことを考えてみてください
we today
今日の私たち
Our twelve-year-old boy today
今日の我が家の12歳の男の子
you speak out
あなたは声を上げます
what great words did you say
あなたはどんな素晴らしい言葉を言いましたか
ok
Ok
jesus may be an exception
イエスは例外かもしれない
He may speak of some of the greater
彼はもっと偉大なことについて話すかもしれない
these words come out
こういう言葉が出てくる
But those of his contemporaries
しかし、彼の同時代の人たちは、
How can there be such a skill?
どうしてそのようなスキルが存在するのでしょうか？
so
それで
This part about this is actually quite reasonable.
これに関するこの部分は、実際には非常に合理的です。
The so-called vulgarism
所謂vulgarism
ok this kind of question
わかりました、この種の質問
written ok
OKと書かれた
It's hard to tell about the appointment
予定について伝えるのは難しい
What about the spirit of writing?
書く精神についてはどうですか？
varying levels of education
さまざまな教育レベル
ok, for example, the Gospel of Matthew, this Matthew
わかりました、たとえばマタイの福音書、このマタイ
Ma Dou La
マ・ドゥ・ラ
catholic horse beans
カトリックの馬豆
ok horse bean gospel
ok 馬豆福音
Ma Dou is a person with a very good education
マドゥは非常に優れた教育を受けた人です
ok the Gospel of John that's another story
オーケー、ヨハネの福音書、それはまた別の話
john is a dreamer
ジョンは夢想家です
dreaming all day long
一日中夢を見ている
one crashed
1台が墜落した
ok and he's a crash
わかった、彼はクラッシュだ
So his text compares
彼のテキストを比較すると、
more vulgar
もっと下品な
ok, what about the letter collection
さて、手紙のコレクションはどうですか
Letters
手紙
The biggest trick in the letter collection is Paul.
手紙集の最大の仕掛け人はポールです。
ok paul
オーケー、ポール
ok paul this them
オーケー、ポール、これは彼らだ
Catholics don't teach Paul
カトリック教徒はパウロを教えない
ok catholic another
オーケー、カトリックもう一つ
this lecture
この講義
like the words of paul
パウロの言葉のように
Paul is a senior intellectual
ポールは上級知識人です
He was very well trained in monasticism
彼は修道院生活について非常によく訓練を受けていました
So Paul's epistles
それでパウロの手紙は
he wrote nine letters
彼は9通の手紙を書きました
Wrote nine letters to Canadians
カナダ人に9通の手紙を書きました
to the romans
ローマ人へ
give where where where
どこにどこにどこに与える
connecting the entire mediterranean
地中海全体を繋ぐ
all the way to australia
はるばるオーストラリアまで
nine cities
9つの都市
Christians
キリスト教徒
string it together
それをつなぎ合わせて
so actually
それで実際に
I should say so
そう言うべきだろう
this catholic
このカトリック教徒
Jesus didn't invent it
イエスが発明したわけではない
not created by him
彼が作ったものではない
Jesus actually thought he was a
イエスは実際に自分を
How to say
どのように言って
a prophet in Judaism
ユダヤ教における預言者
This is his definition of who he is
これが彼が誰であるかの定義です
really take this catholic
本当にこのカトリック教徒を受け入れてください
or to put the thought of jesus
あるいはイエスの思いを込めて
believers in jesus
イエスを信じる者
this person connected
この人はつながっている
it's paul
ポールです
It was Paul's contribution
それはポールの貢献でした
So we often say that Paul is
それで私たちはよく「パウロはこうだ」と言います。
true founder of catholicism
カトリックの真の創始者
jesus is not
イエスはそうではありません
OK
OK
then anyway what i want to say is to say
それでとにかく私が言いたいのは、
paul he is actually a
ポール彼は実際には
a man who is very well trained in rhetoric
レトリックの訓練を非常によく受けている男性
especially experienced
特に経験豊富な
The so-called judicial rhetoric
いわゆる司法レトリック
OK
OK
This training in courtroom rhetoric
法廷でのレトリックに関するこのトレーニング
in court like a lawyer
弁護士のように法廷で
able to talk to others
他の人と話すことができる
debate with others
他の人と議論する
OK
OK
He's been very well trained in this area
彼はこの分野で非常によく訓練されています
So the Pauline letter is
つまり、パウロの手紙は、
it is written
書くのは
How to say Wang Yang knowledge
王陽知識の言い方
OK
OK
this one
これです
this kind
この種
this reasoning
この推論
OK
OK
debate
議論
It's almost diabolical
それはほとんど悪魔的だ
ok let you down
わかりました、がっかりさせてください
make you feel say
言う気分にさせる
Anyway, what you said seems to be the most correct.
とにかく、あなたの言ったことは最も正しいようです。
ok, so the wish is a bit more difficult to say
さて、願いを言うのは少し難しいです
It's different when you go to the Discrimination Register
差別登録所に行くと違います
The discrimination record is actually made by the local one.
差別記録は実際に地元の方が作成したものです。
this one this book
これ、この本
Sorry, I have Tian Bishops here.
申し訳ありませんが、ここにはティアン司教がいます。
I'm christian
私はクリスチャンです
because i'm not a gangster
私はギャングではないので
I sometimes speak and compare
時々話したり比べたりする
From the point of view of our secular world
私たちの世俗的な世界の観点から見ると
Discrimination record you all know
皆さんご存知の差別記録
The discriminatory record is only inside
差別歴は内部のみ
It's all a myth, isn't it?
それはすべて神話ですよね？
The issue of discrimination
差別の問題
That style is quite low style
そのスタイルはかなりのロースタイルです
That is to say it is not very elegant style
つまり、あまりエレガントなスタイルではありません
ok so wish it had this
わかりました、これがあればいいのに
it doesn't have to
その必要はない
it has elegance
優雅さがあります
Some are lower
一部は低いです
ok so this congratulatory belt
はい、それではこのご祝儀ベルトです
He's pretty awesome
彼はかなりすごいです
When he met this Xinyue
彼がこのXinyueに出会ったとき
he will become a problem
彼は問題になるだろう
OK he will be a problem
OK、彼は問題になるだろう
This is what we have been teaching students on the translation
これが私たちが翻訳に関して生徒たちに教えてきたことです
I am in the Institute of Translation Research
私は翻訳研究所に所属しています
Persevere OK
頑張れOK
Then I often teach students that
それから、私はよく生徒たちにこう言います。
You can translate consciousness
意識を翻訳できる
It's just a basic job
あくまで基本的な仕事です
What you should really be doing is
本当にやるべきことは、
Translate people's questions
人々の質問を翻訳する
Translate other people's style
他の人のスタイルを翻訳する
that's it
それでおしまい
To complete this job of this translation, let's say
この翻訳という作業を完了するには、次のようにします。
OK
OK
We have too much of this in foreign countries
外国にはこういうものが多すぎる
sinologist
中国学者
OK
OK
Whether Chinese or foreigners
中国人でも外国人でも
78 weeks after this was dug out
これが発掘されてから78週間後
After Du Fu was dug out again, there was no difference between Du Fu that week.
杜甫が再び掘り出された後、その週は杜甫に差はなかった。
OK
OK
What about us in Taiwan?
台湾ではどうですか？
same ok
同じですよ
Then lose the round British 19th century romantic teacher
そして、丸い英国の19世紀のロマンチックな教師を失います
Number kids19th century romantic teacher
ナンバーキッズ19世紀のロマンチックな先生
You learned this shirley from a 19th century romantic teacher
あなたはこのシャーリーを 19 世紀のロマンチックな教師から学びました
After you translate it into Chinese
中国語に翻訳したら
Those three people are also a total of one person
その3人も合わせて1人です
Turned out that the English style is gone
英国式はなくなったことが判明
You just pass the message out
あなたはただメッセージを伝えるだけです
Then send this message
それからこのメッセージを送信してください
problem didn't come out
問題は出なかった
So how can you say your translation is a successful one?
では、どうすれば翻訳が成功していると言えるのでしょうか?
you turn to the end you will find
最後まで目を向ければ見つかるでしょう
if say you have some translators
翻訳者が何人かいるとします
when he went on
彼が続けたとき
You find that what he translates is actually
彼が翻訳した内容は実際には次のとおりであることがわかります。
His translation of SARS Biya is quite anti-French
彼のSARS Biyaの翻訳はかなり反フランス語的だ
That is to say, the first-class SARS Biya
つまり、ファーストクラスのSARSビヤ
Follow him to read second-rate and third-rate Western writers
彼に従って西洋の二流作家と三流作家を読んでください
The problem is the same style is the same
問題は、同じスタイルは同じということです
this change
この変化
it's a pity
それは残念だ
But it's hard to teach students
でも生徒に教えるのは難しい
Let them fully understand this style
このスタイルをしっかりと理解してもらう
how important
どれほど重要か
Naga Jinna is very clear
ナーガ・ジンナは非常に明確です
this one person
この一人の人
This dream that actually gave birth to Jerome
この夢が実際にジェロームを生み出した
this dream
この夢
In fact, posterity later inspected this textual research
実際、後世の人々がこの文書研究を調べました。
Jerome's dream
ジェロームの夢
actually sitting here
実際にここに座っています
he started this translation bible
彼はこの翻訳聖書を書き始めました
years ago
数年前
Ok
Ok
So he actually translated the Bible with this
それで彼は実際にこれで聖書を翻訳しました
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
But in the end it will be our human ability
でも結局は人間の能力なんだよ
Ok
Ok
this history of translation
この翻訳の歴史
Just take this Jerome's dream
まさにこのジェロームの夢
Ok
Ok
Why use this with Jerome
ジェロームでこれを使用する理由
so-called general book
所謂的通書的
Latin to translate the bible
ラテン語で聖書を翻訳する
just combine it
それを組み合わせるだけです
OK
OK
the useless one
役に立たないもの
this bible
この聖書
This is called Homeless Big Ben
ここはホームレスビッグベンと呼ばれています
this is chinese
これは中国人です
OK in English
英語でOK
The Vulgate Bible
ウルガタ聖書
OK
OK
The Latin word for English is called
英語を表すラテン語はこう呼ばれます
Knife
ナイフ
OK
OK
this homeless man
このホームレスの男性
this bible
この聖書
where is the big homeless bible
ホームレスの大きな聖書はどこにありますか
this
これ
no
いいえ
this one
これです
how to say that
それをどう言うか
similar
類似
similar to this one
これに似たもの
Plaintext
平文
OK
OK
Or
また
similar
類似
don't speak plain language
平易な言葉を話さないでください
It doesn't even look like stereotyped essays
型にはまったエッセイにも見えない
OK
OK
it is totally used
完全に使われています
in the market
市場で
those
それらの
so-called peddling
いわゆる行商
The so-called speculators who sell ginger
生姜を売るいわゆる投機家たち
OK
OK
It's the mother-in-law in the market
市場の義母です
them
彼ら
translate this bible in their words
この聖書を彼らの言葉で翻訳してください
So five big bibles
つまり5つの大きな聖書
The five big bibles are in the era of about
五大聖書はおよその時代にあります。
around the fourth century
4世紀頃
this Yoshimaru
この吉丸
Tunnel fifth century
坑道五世紀
I don't know remember
分からない覚えてる
Because after Yoshimaru
因為他義丸之後
until this
これまで
Probably around 1592
おそらく1592年頃
In fact, the whole of Europe
実はヨーロッパ全体が
They all believe in the five major Bibles
彼らは皆、五大聖書を信じています
Because this is the Church of Rome
ここはローマ教会だから
signed this bible
この聖書に署名しました
you don't need to understand greek
ギリシャ語を理解する必要はありません
you don't need to understand spanish
スペイン語を理解する必要はありません
but you have to understand
しかし理解する必要があります
you can read this bible in latin
この聖書を読むことができる唯一の方法はラテン語です
otherwise
さもないと
you don't understand latin
あなたはラテン語を理解していません
You can at least pronounce that too
あなたも少なくともそれを発音できます
So
それで
Translated five large Bibles
五大聖書を翻訳
is the translation of the Middle Ages throughout Europe
ヨーロッパ全土の中世の翻訳です
until 1592
1592年まで
At that time, it was called Kermit Barst
当時はカーミット・バーストと呼ばれていました
he just thought
彼はただ思った
It seems that throughout the Middle Ages
中世を通じてあったようです
As long as Gutenberg invented printing in 1550
1550年にグーテンベルクが印刷術を発明して以来
before 1550
1550年以前
In fact, what you read about Jiuwenteng
実際、九文騰について読んだこと
It's all this superbook
それはすべてこのスーパーブックです
It's all super on the central grape
中央のブドウはすべて最高です
Ultrabooks are a big problem
Ultrabook は大きな問題です
some people more than one word
人によっては一言以上
Some people have one more word and one less
単語が 1 つ増えたり、1 つ減ったりする人もいます
or not the whole
それとも全体ではないのか
gone, and so on
消えた、など
how am i
私はどうですか
is there any such condition
そのような条件はありますか
Can be long, conceivable situation
長期にわたる可能性がある、考えられる状況
In fact, most of them will have
実際、彼らのほとんどは、
So in 1592 when
それで1592年に
This Climate 80
この気候 80
He finally said no
彼はついにノーと言った
OK, this must be unified
はい、これは統一する必要があります
This one of the five big books
これは五大本の一つです
How to say
どのように言って
His ciphertext is not
彼の暗号文はそうではありません
OK, so this one came out in 1592
OK、これは1592年に発売されたものです
that latin family is called
そのラテン系家族はこう呼ばれています
I Kadan Climateenum
I カダン クライマティーンム
OK, the English translation is called
OK、英語訳はこう呼ばれます
Climate times
気候変動の時代
vulgate
俗語
OK, that is to say
OK、つまり
This is a Climate book
これは気候に関する本です
Big Five
五家大本
Bible
聖書
OK
OK
Then I can be 100% sure that
そうすれば100％確信できます
He Qingpai
賀青派
translate the ancient bible
古代の聖書を翻訳する
must be based on
に基づいている必要があります
With Gartham, Clementine
ガーサム、クレメンタインと
but
しかし
Even if it is this book, the so-called standard text, the Bible
この本、いわゆる定本、聖書であっても
In fact, there are various Versions versions
実際にはさまざまなバージョンがあります
Some have gaps, some don't
隙間があるものもあれば、ないものもあります
There is this one, with possible punctuation
これには句読点が含まれる可能性があります
In fact, punctuation marks were rarely used at that time.
実際、当時は句読点はほとんど使用されていませんでした。
this is late
これは遅いです
so
それで
in the end want
結局欲しい
If we do this today, then we do this today
今日これをするなら、今日もこれをする
I already have 36 volumes of this
これもう36巻持ってる
this
これ
fruit new bible
フルーツの新しい聖書
Then we're going to find this for the 36 volumes of the Guoxin Bible
次に、国信聖書の 36 巻についてこれを見つけます。
This is the first book
これが最初の本です
ok
Ok
It's not that easy
そんなに簡単じゃないよ
Why is it not such an easy thing?
なぜそんなに簡単なことではないのでしょうか？
actually
実際
The reason for this should be your replacement chief.
その理由はあなたの後任の主任にあるはずです。
ok
Ok
The reason is this
理由はこれです
There are some libraries in the mainland
本土にはいくつかの図書館があります
OK
OK
Until now
今まで
Probably not very willing to let you read his book.
おそらく、あなたに彼の本を読ませる気はあまりないでしょう。
OK
OK
Whether it is He Jin, he has always lived in Beitang
何進にせよ、彼は常に北塘に住んでいます
Bei Tang in Beijing
北京の北堂
Beitang is by the sea, that area, Peking University
北塘は海のそば、あの辺、北京大学
that area
その地域
OK
OK
this North Tang
この北唐
Actually own a really good one
実は本当に良いものを所有している
The library is like our newer education before
図書館は以前の私たちの新しい教育のようなものです
A pretty awesome library like
かなり素晴らしいライブラリのような
Northern Tang Book
北唐書
Northern Tang's book dream
北唐の本の夢
actually exceeded
実際に超えた
Shumeng of Beitang, you let go of Shumeng of Beitang, there are quite a few of them
北塘のシュメン、あなたは北塘のシュメンを手放します、それらはかなりの数あります
The big price version of this
これの高額版
Bible
聖書
The Christian edition of this bible
この聖書のキリスト教版
there are quite a few
かなりの数があります
also super same
それも超同じ
even more
さらにもっと
OK
OK
Where is the dream in this book?
この本のどこに夢があるのでしょうか？
clearly recorded
明確に記録されている
but you have to take
しかし、あなたは取らなければなりません
There just happens to be this very, very interesting coincidence
とても、とても興味深い偶然が偶然起こったのです
i've been watching this
私はこれを見てきました
Previously this was a magazine published in Zhejiang
以前は浙江省で発行されていた雑誌でした
It's called "Shangzi Compilation Library Journal"
その名も「尚子編纂蔵書誌」
There is still a university in Japan called "Shangzi University", right?
日本には「尚子大学」という大学がまだありますよね。
Then this "Shangzi Compilation Library Journal"
それからこの『尚子編纂蔵書誌』
It contains the special script for Northern Tibet
北チベットの特別な文字が含まれています
Then pointed out that Mrs. He Jin once had a heart attack
そして何進夫人がかつて心臓発作を起こしたことがあると指摘した。
This operation of the 15 cards of the magic guard
マジックガードの15枚のカードのこの操作
Of course, these operations will not be fun later
もちろん、これらの操作は後で楽しくありません
When it's time for the tuition fee, it will take the class by the way.
授業料の時期になると、ついでに授業を受けます。
So in fact, if we say that there is a way
それで実際に方法があると言ったら
Put this North Tibet by the way because those
ところで、この北チベットのことは脇に置いておいてください。
so much of this nerve
この神経の多さ
Let's match each other
お互いにマッチングしましょう
If the operation of these 15 cards
この15枚のカードを運用すれば
if you are there
あなたがそこにいるなら
So
それで
cooperate
協力する
we all know
私たちは皆知っています
Which book is He Jinjia based on
何金佳はどの本に基づいていますか
this one
これです
Well
良い
clament version of this one
これのクラムバージョン
Um
えーっと
The Five Great Ones
五大偉人
OK
OK
Well
良い
But because
しかし理由は
Some
いくつかの
Well
良い
some causes of noise some noise
ノイズの原因 いくつかのノイズ
OK
OK
so
それで
You have to look for this bibliography in the Northern Collection
この参考文献は北方コレクションで探す必要があります。
He Jin’s all this specific version
ヘ・ジンのこの特別なバージョン
Well
良い
People in difficulty today from
今日、困難に直面している人々は、
in ours
私たちの中で
Well
良い
Before Xu Jiahui in this continent
この大陸の徐家輝以前
Xu Jiahui didn't even know that he had a book called
徐家輝さんは、自分が次のような本を出版していることさえ知りませんでした。
old and new biblical
古くて新しい聖書
OK
OK
he has a herb
彼は薬草を持っています
called the Old New Bible
旧新聖書と呼ばれる
Xu Jiahui doesn't know
徐家輝は知らない
OK
OK
so uh
それで、ええと
How to say
どのように言って
this book
この本
The basic problem is
基本的な問題は
a quite
かなり
big one question
大きな質問
pretty good
かなり良い
OK
OK
So
それで
Well
良い
You can still find out
まだ知ることができます
He Jinjia
賀金家
On some version issues related to the script
スクリプトに関連する一部のバージョンの問題について
This man is bold
この人は大胆だ
OK how to say
OK、なんと言うか
He not only divides this creation into spirits
彼はこの創造物を精霊に分割するだけではありません
and the spirit of creation
そして創造の精神
A little bit more detailed on this preference
この設定についてもう少し詳しく説明します
He also has something different in this place
彼はここでも何か違うものを持っています
OK, for example, Diamond King Jing is Liu Wang Ji
OK、たとえば、ダイヤモンド・キング・ジンは劉王基です。
OK Volume 10 has a total of 26 articles
OK ボリューム 10 には合計 26 個の記事があります
In fact, it is better than the Clementine version of the five elders themselves
実際、クレメンタイン版の五長老そのものよりも優れています。
one extra
余分に1つ
His so-called bias is actually what we call dirty now
彼のいわゆる偏見は、実際には今私たちが汚いものと呼んでいるものです
One more OK
もう一つOK
That's because we built it because
それは私たちがそれを構築したからです
He Jin, there will be one shaya left
ヘ・ジン、シャヤは一人残るだろう
Chapter 38 of Leftover Essence
残りのエッセンスの章 38
Dirty beautician for this Hazakill
このハザキルの汚い美容師
He won it to the tenth volume of this diamond king
彼はこのダイヤモンドキングの10巻に勝ちました
dubbed into a drill
ドリルに吹き込まれた
drill articles
ドリル記事
OK, but He Jinhai, he can be honest, he will tell you, this poem, I got it here from this slow place, OK, this is what I think He Jinhai, I actually don't understand how this guy is so bold, he dared to cut your Bible, OK, he dared to cut your Bible, so even if you want to find this one with his,
OK、でもヘ・ジンハイ、彼は正直に言うことができる、彼はあなたにこの詩を教えてくれる、私はこの遅い場所からここにそれを持ってきました、OK、これが私が思うことです ヘ・ジンハイ、私は実際のところ、どうしてこの人がそんなに大胆なのか理解できません、彼はあえてあなたの聖書を切りました、わかりました、彼はあえてあなたの聖書を切りました、だからあなたがこれを彼のもので見つけたいとしても、
This Bible Zhang Jie, biased, biased, biased, is exactly the same as this Bible,
この聖書の張潔は、偏っていて、偏っていて、偏っていて、この聖書とまったく同じです。
I'm afraid, the first one is not easy, so what if you find the second one, OK, He Jinhai is actually very clear about why he wants to change these things, OK, so these are actually quite
申し訳ありませんが、最初のものは簡単ではありません。それで、2 番目のものを見つけたらどうしますか、OK、ヘ ジンハイはこれらのことを変更したい理由について実際に非常に明確です、わかりました、つまり、これらは実際には非常に重要です
First of all, we are now waiting for sex,
まず第一に、私たちは今セックスを待っています、
materials are limited
材料は限られている
Some koans in the biblical conference history
聖書会議の歴史におけるいくつかの公案
so
それで
I see a lot of this bible to the end
私はこの聖書を最後までよく見ます
I now at least I now say this whole
私は今、少なくともこれを全部言います
The last sentence
最後一句
This five-big bible in the Crano edition
クラノ版の5大バイブル
is to solve the first problem
最初の問題を解決することです
as of today
今日現在
largest common divisor
最大公約数
OK
OK
This is about China National Investment Pavilion
これは中国国家投資パビリオンについてです
his this
彼のこれ
If he didn't open the last book
上本書他不開放的話
Because all the books in Beijing are used later
北京にある本は全部後で使うから
After 49 years, all rely on this
49年経っても、みんなこれに頼る
This area of ​​China National Investment Pavilion
中国国家投資パビリオンのこのエリア
he is not open
他不開放
OK like a baby
大丈夫、赤ちゃんみたいに
OK
OK
we will always be
私たちはいつもそうなります
This problem will never be solved
この問題は永遠に続くので、解決する方法はありません。
OK
OK
itself is a public opinion
それ自体が世論です
So He Jinnai in a yes indeed
だからヘ・ジンナイは確かにイエスだ
There are some arrangements in the Bible
聖書にはいくつかの取り決めがあります
yes there are some very very surprising
はい、非常に驚​​くべきことがいくつかあります
surprise arrangement
サプライズアレンジメント
OK
OK
then the future
それから未来
What I pay more attention to is He Qingtai's language problem
私がもっと注目しているのは、何清台の言語の問題です。
Because this is the first vernacular
これが最初の言葉だから
our nerves
私たちの神経
So when we get it, we must pay attention to
したがって、それを取得したとき、私たちは次のことに注意を払う必要があります
vernacular these two words
日常的なこの 2 つの単語
OK
OK
Then we say that we don't like the word
それから私たちはその言葉が好きではないと言います
it's a copy of this one
それはこれのコピーです
The so-called Mandarin Bible
いわゆる北京語聖書
People are because of He Qingtai
人々は何清台のおかげです
the text he used
彼が使用したテキスト
actually quite
実際かなり
you are familiar
あなたはよく知っています
quite familiar
かなりおなじみの
you can say this
あなたはこれを言うことができます
OK
OK
and it has some
そしてそれはいくつかあります
Very
非常
very interesting special usage
非常に興味深い特殊な使用法
Here I first demonstrate that
ここで私は最初にそれを証明します
Before He Shengtai
何盛台の前に
also which catholic masters
また、どのカトリックのマスターも
here's some translation of the bible
ここに聖書の翻訳があります
This one is called
これはと呼ばれます
Yuen Long Nok's One
元朗ノックズワン
a missionary in spain
スペインの宣教師
in his 1636
1636年に
I wrote a book called Verses of the Bible
私は聖書の一節という本を書きました
but no
でもいいえ
Don't follow the subtitles
字幕を追ってはいけない
OK
OK
this bible verse
この聖書の一節
The national translation of the Bible is not here
聖書の国内訳はここにはありません
holy bible
聖書
It's three pairs of the so-called
いわゆる3ペアです
bible study time
聖書の勉強の時間
This verse that everyone should read
誰もが読むべきこの聖句
So the book of bible verses
それで、聖書の一節の本は
although very thick
非常に厚いですが
But
しかし
it
それ
it only means probably
おそらく意味するだけです
fifty three
五十三
About fifty-four weeks a year
年間約54週間
fifty three four weeks
534週間
Fifty-Three Four Pasagis
フィフティ・スリー・フォー・パサジス
OK
OK
nothing more
これ以上何もない
Then these Pasagis
それからこのパサギたち
it will add some explanation
説明を追加します
this explanation
この説明
Then it uses the word intuition
それから直感という言葉を使います
But that explanation is still quite far
しかし、その説明はまだかなり遠いです
OK
OK
Yang Maruo translates this Holy Spirit Son's Day
ヤン・マルオがこの聖霊の子の日を翻訳
was in 1639
1639年のことでした
Before Yang Maruo
ヤン・マルオ以前
Actually Ai Weiwei translated this again
実はアイ・ウェイウェイがこれを再翻訳しました
The so-called incarnation of God is fierce in words and deeds
いわゆる神の化身は言葉も行為も激しい
This is a so-called gospel and technology
これはいわゆる福音とテクノロジーです
In fact, this is the first book
実はこれが初めての本です
This first book is called
この最初の本は次のように呼ばれています
Wita Christi
ウィタ・クリスティ
OK
OK
Life of Christ
キリストの生涯
holy son
聖なる息子
sorry for the harsh comment
厳しいコメントでごめんなさい
OK
OK
Yang Maruo this
ヤン・マルオこれ
I'm sorry when Ai Weiwei translated
アイ・ウェイウェイが翻訳したときはごめんなさい
this
これ
He said he dared not speak up
彼はあえて声を上げなかったと言った
OK
OK
because
なぜなら
that book and this
あの本とこれ
In this Holy Spirit he knew
この聖霊の中で彼は知っていました
also lost this gospel
この福音も失った
OK
OK
because said album
だってあのアルバム
there is a little difference
少し違いがあります
So he said he dare not speak righteously
だから彼は正義を語る勇気はないと言った
In any case, he is still a text-to-text translator
いずれにせよ、彼は依然としてテキストからテキストへの翻訳者です
The time closest to He Jintai is Paris Foreign Mission Society
何金台に最も近い時間はパリ外国宣教会です
A man named Bai Yusheng
白玉生という男
The book he translated is called "The Gospel of Facts as Unwilling"
彼が翻訳した本は「不本意としての事実の福音」と呼ばれています。
This so-called fact refers to the "Master's Blessings in Books"
このいわゆる事実は、「書物における師の祝福」を指します。
He deleted the repetition of "Fu Yu Shu"
彼は「Fu Yu Shu」の繰り返しを削除しました。
Organize a non-overlapping turn of Jesus
イエスのターンを重複しないように整理する
This is still Chinese
これでもまだ中華だよな
only near too
あまりにも近いだけ
close too finally think
近くにもついに考える
according to him
彼によると
He thinks I should learn English or not
彼は私が英語を勉強すべきかどうか考えている
You shouldn't learn this sutra of love without meaning
この愛の経典を意味もなく学んではいけない
I have to be busy
忙しくなければなりません
Because he landed from Macau
マカオから上陸したので
What about after going ashore?
上陸後はどうでしょうか？
started contacting this one
この人に連絡し始めました
Continue to learn the commissioner
コミッショナーについて学び続ける
ok you
わかりました、あなた
In fact, the contact is the book
実際、連絡先は本です
For me, the above book is the one that should be changed to
私にとって、上記の本は次のように変更すべき本です
up in the sky
空の上に
ok
Ok
That is to say
つまり
It's a bible
それは聖書です
i don't understand him at all
私は彼のことを全く理解できません
ok
Ok
gave this annotation
この注釈を付けました
Sometimes I doubt it, just comment
時々疑問に思うこともありますが、コメントしてください
right?
右？
ok
Ok
So writing a letter is certainly not that simple.
したがって、手紙を書くことは確かにそれほど簡単ではありません。
a book
一冊の本
The style of the book
本のスタイル
ok actually quite
わかりました、実際かなり
difficult
難しい
ok
Ok
then this
それからこれ
this
これ
festival of sound
音の祭典
Just use this to go to the book and go to the book
これを使って本に行き、本に行くだけです
Be your good Moz body
良いモズボディになりましょう
to translate
翻訳すること
ok
Ok
Learn from his book The Book of Voices to be honest
正直に言うと、彼の著書『The Book of Voices』から学びましょう
I really doubt how many people can read it
本当にどれだけの人が読めるのか疑問です
ok, that proves that there will be a problem involved
OK、それは問題が関係していることを証明しています
Normal sound pronunciation, but rarely pay attention to say
普通の音の発音ですが、注意して言うことはほとんどありません
are you right or wrong
あなたは正しいですか、それとも間違っていますか
ok, right or wrong, originally
オーケー、正しくても間違っていても、元々は
I should have been right
私は正しかったはずだ
ok, that's the right one
わかりました、それが正しいです
ok, actually very
わかりました、実際にはとても
A very off track concept
非常に軌道から外れたコンセプト
ok, this is for
わかりました、これは
In other words, this Chinese time translates the above Chinese time
つまり、この中国時間は上記の中国時間を翻訳したものになります。
what should be timed with
何とタイミングを合わせるべきか
That's actually a very derailed question.
それは実際には非常に脱線した質問です。
Let me give you an example, because I don't understand
理解できないので例を挙げてみましょう
I am not a bible expert
私は聖書の専門家ではありません
I'm not, I don't understand Hebrew
違います、ヘブライ語がわかりません
ok, my friend is Professor Li Zhichang from the Chinese University of Hong Kong
はい、私の友人は香港中文大学の李志昌教授です。
I also invited him to this accountability office, this one to give a speech
私はまた、彼をこの会計事務所に招待し、スピーチをさせました。
and play this river river
そしてこの川で遊んでください
OK
OK
He said this when He Heben opened
He Hebenを開いたときに彼はこう言いました
Well, this god doesn't know how many days
まあ、何日かかるかは神には分からない
Created a head
頭を作成しました
Because what we want to translate is called
私たちが翻訳したいのは
Sea Monster
シーモンスター
OK
OK
sea ​​monster
海の怪物
A thing like this came out of this one
この中からこんなのが出てきました
right
右
God didn't invent anything
神は何も発明しなかった
He'll say um, that's good
彼は言うでしょう、ええと、それは良いです
OK
OK
You found out he said the monster came out and he also said um it's good
彼はモンスターが出てきたと言って、それはいいことだとも言っていたことがわかりましたね
Well
良い
did you react like that
あなたはそのように反応しましたか
Just learned this everyone
みんなこれ習ったよ
how to ask
どのように尋ねるか
Do you just follow along?
ただ従うだけですか？
OK
OK
If you want to turn it according to
に従って回転させたい場合は、
I think the church will revolutionize
教会は革命を起こすと思う
OK
OK
uh no
うーん、いいえ
They don't dare to flip like that
彼らはそんなひっくり返る勇気はない
OK
OK
uh they use this uh
ああ、彼らはこれを使っています ああ
how to say
どのように言って
Uh, the tone is a bit more complete.
うーん、トーンがもう少し完成しました。
Go get this Sea Monster
この海の怪物を捕まえに行きます
The concept warms it up
コンセプトはそれを温めます
so that you don't feel so strong when you read it
読んでもそんなに強い気持ちにならないように
Holy land actually created a monster
聖地は実際にモンスターを生み出した
So this is the holy yin range
これが聖陰の範囲です
In fact, the scope of Buddhism is almost the same
実は仏教の範囲はほぼ同じです
often occur
頻繁に起こる
guru is guru in teaching
グルは教える上でのグルです
not guru yu original text
原文では教祖ではなく
Our general current concept is translation
現在の私たちの一般的なコンセプトは翻訳です
It should be Guru Yu's original text
Guru Yu の原文のはずです
No way
とんでもない
This word has never existed since
この言葉は今までなかった
Until today, the combined practice book
今日までの総合練習帳
None of them are masters in the original text
原文では誰もマスターではありません
all masters
すべてのマスターと教え
Including this big book
この分厚い本も含めて
while translating
翻訳しながら
Nine clouds in Jerusalem
エルサレムの九つの雲
study at the university
大学で勉強する
learn a western
西部劇を学ぶ
while in jerusalem
エルサレムにいる間
bible
聖書
OK
OK
St. Augustine
セント オーガスティン
Augustine
アウグスティヌス
OK
OK
Well in Rome this one
さて、ローマではこれです
As soon as I hear that he is translating this one, I will make an appointment.
彼がこれを翻訳していると聞いたら、すぐに予約を取るつもりです。
write a letter now
今すぐ手紙を書いてください
This one went to Jerusalem and gave him
この人はエルサレムに行き、彼に与えました
what's in the letter
手紙の内容は何ですか
The original text you are reading now
今読んでいる原文
If this subtogent of our faith
もしこれが私たちの信仰の帰属であるなら、
OK
OK
This is the Greek word for
これはギリシャ語で
if there is no bottom
底がなかったら
you can translate
翻訳できます
OK
OK
if there is a bottom
底があるなら
please don't translate it
翻訳しないでください
OK
OK
you make this one wrong
あなたはこれを間違っています
Let him be wrong until the end
最後まで彼に間違ったままにしておいてください
OK
OK
the bible is often like this
聖書はよくこんな感じです
because if you don't
なぜなら、そうしないと
I'm really going to make this
本当にこれを作るつもりです
this this this
これこれこれ
education becomes this one
教育はこれになる
there will be a minute hand
分針があるでしょう
OK
OK
if there is a minute hand
長針がある場合
That's what makes the church unrest
それが教会を不安にさせる原因です
In ancient times, the west was the orthodox education system
古代、西洋は正統的な教育システムでした
church unrest
教会の暴動
will definitely affect
間違いなく影響するだろう
to the issue of politics
政治の問題に
so this is a very big question
これはとても大きな質問です
So I often say this word stock since
だから私はこの株という言葉をよく言います。
Religious translation this support is
宗教翻訳このサポートは
The most should be to the original text should be the most
原文に最も近いものである必要があります。
The most faithful ok but
最も忠実なのはわかりますが、
no way ok is often the most unfaithful
いいえ、OK は多くの場合、最も不誠実です
ok this this this
はい、これ、これ
how do you say this
どのようにこれを言うのですか
translate this
これを訳して
the content of the problem
問題の内容
but because of the content
でも内容のせいで
Already framed by this teaching
すでにこの教えに組み込まれている
so generally
とても一般的に
translating this
これを翻訳しています
when the sound is actually
実際に音が鳴るとき
What everyone pays attention to is
みんなが注目しているのは、
what do i want to use
何を使いたいですか
style to translate the sound
音を翻訳するスタイル
ok then some Augustine
さて、それではアウグスティヌス
he wrote a book called
彼はという本を書きました
on Christian doctrine ok
キリスト教の教義に関してはOK
because at this time
なぜなら現時点では
he christianity has not yet appeared
彼はキリスト教はまだ現れていない
So I dare not translate him into tenure
だから私はあえて彼を在職期間に移すつもりはない
I can only translate it as this Catholicism
これはカトリックとしか訳せません
It develops from Cicero's view the so-called free types of style
キケロの見解に基づいて、いわゆる自由なスタイルを発展させたものです。
This style divides it into three bodies
3体に分けるスタイルです
There are so-called high-level questions
いわゆる高度な質問があります
There are so-called intermediate problems
いわゆる中間問題があります
or intermediate questions
または中程度の質問
There are also so-called low-level problems
いわゆる低レベルの問題もあります
or the so-called flat problem
またはいわゆるフラット問題
These three styles do not actually represent
これら 3 つのスタイルは実際には表しません
Which one is good or which one is bad
どっちがいいのか、どっちが悪いのか
It only has the function above this function
この機能以上の機能しかありません
as i speak to you now
私が今あなたに話しているように
I can't this seems to be in
これは入っているようです
The general is lecturing
将軍が講義中
When asking troops to fight
軍隊に戦闘を要請する場合
I speak in a very, very high style
私はとてもとても上品なスタイルで話します
I can probably only use the kind of words that you can understand, which is more straightforward.
私はおそらくあなたが理解できるより直接的な言葉しか使うことができないでしょう
Let's talk about the old and the new Bible
新旧の聖書について話しましょう
So I actually use the third kind of problem
そこで私は実際に 3 番目の種類の問題を使用します
So I just accidentally ran out sometimes
だから時々うっかり足りなくなってしまうことがある
For example, draw something like this
たとえば、次のようなものを描きます
these three questions
この3つの質問
The bear tail problem is of course to move
クマの尻尾の問題はもちろん移動です
want one person
一人欲しい
The central problem is to make people feel like making up
中心的な問題は人々に仲直りしたいと思わせることだ
full of comfort and happiness
快適さと幸せに満ちた
the straight question or the low level question
ストレートな質問または低レベルの質問
His purpose is to teach
彼の目的は教えることです
So most of us as teachers actually teach people
したがって、教師である私たちのほとんどは実際に人々に教えています
It's all about quality
すべては品質です
Although these three questions
この３つの質問ですが、
Not that you are in the same article
同じ記事に載っているわけではない
Or in the same speech
あるいは同じスピーチの中で
You have always chosen a style to use
あなたはいつも使用するスタイルを選択してきました
you often know three
あなたはよく3つを知っています
will mix
混ぜます
He Jinnai from 9M
9Mのヘ・ジンナイ
The concept of that dream is
その夢のコンセプトは
He has to use the third question to translate the bible
彼は聖書を翻訳するために 3 番目の質問を使用しなければなりません
I'm hanging a new section here
ここに新しいセクションを追加します
Because the situation is a bit special
ちょっと特殊な状況なので
a little exception
ちょっとした例外
He's bad for this little Marlowe
この小さなマーロウには悪い奴だ
My I56 uses 5A to apply
私の I56 は 5A を使用して適用します
parent number font
親番号フォント
use this
これを使って
Use this variety show
このバラエティ番組を利用してください
He Jinnai's emphasis on this article
この記事に対するヘ・ジンナイの強調
only say this bible
この聖書だけを言います
What we should pay attention to is
私たちが注意すべきことは、
This truth in the Bible
聖書のこの真実
the word find or sentence
単語または文を見つける
In fact, God still has this blood spirit man
実際、神はまだこの血の霊人を持っています
Actually it doesn't matter
実際にはそれは関係ありません
OK, don't take it too seriously
OK、あまり真剣に考えないでください
OK
OK
What is this Planes style
なんだこのプレーンズスタイルは
What about quality issues?
品質の問題についてはどうですか？
St. Augustine's definition is
聖オーガスティンの定義は、
The statement is relatively peaceful
発言は比較的平和的
more mature
比較成熟
no such premature death
そんな早死にはない
He is closer to the masses
彼は大衆に近い
So I said He Qingtai
それで私は何青台と言った
At least when he's translating in real vernacular
少なくとも彼が実際の言葉で翻訳しているときは
He doesn't use Mandarin
彼は中国語を使いません
It is translating in Beijing dialect
代わりに北京語に翻訳しています
OK
OK
his translation is very
彼の翻訳はとても素晴らしい
Sometimes this, this, this, how to say
時々これ、これ、これ、なんて言うか
After all, it is written exclusively for foreigners
やっぱり外国人向けに書かれているんですね
OK
OK
Often some of this writes
多くの場合、この記事の一部は
there are some laws
いくつかの法律があります
is to make ourselves very stimulating
自分自身をとても刺激的にすることです
For example
例えば
you translated that one word
あなたはその一言を翻訳しました
OK
OK
did i make a word
私は言葉を作りましたか
Then say the word war of this war
それならこの戦争について戦争という言葉を言ってください
His usage is the same as our current usage
彼の使用法は私たちの現在の使用法と同じです
I'm afraid it's very different
かなり違うと思います
OK
OK
Feliz
ハッピー
Feliz Dunn
フェリス・ダン
This Feliz Dunn
このフェリス・ダン
Really come to fight
本当に戦いに来てください
OK
OK
About Abel and his parables come to fight
アベルと彼の戦うたとえ話について
Saiba
サイバ
OK
OK
I think there's a real battle here
ここに本当の戦いがあると思う
This battle is a
この戦いは、
Is a verb that does not care to explain in English
英語で説明する必要のない動詞です
OK
OK
Then let's fight Saiba
じゃあサイバと戦いましょう
And I used it as a verb, OK
再び動詞として使用してもOK
Actually we rarely use this one
実はこれはほとんど使いません
this
これ
Two usages of this actually we
これの 2 つの使用法は、実際には
except dialect
方言を除く
OK
OK
We rarely have this in Mandarin.
北京語ではこれがほとんどありません。
Think of war as an OK that counts verbs but not verbs, we are
戦争を、動詞はカウントするが動詞はカウントしないOKだと考えてください。
fight
喧嘩
right
右
Fighting on both sides OK
両側で戦ってもOK
he doesn't talk like that
彼はそんな風には話さない
he was in that era
彼はその時代にいた
in the former home era
かつてのホーム時代に
he would say that
彼はそう言うだろう
St below
セント・アンダー
yes
はい
Sentifly
センティフライ
Colorful
カラフル
or Dediculate
または献身的
these two words
この二つの言葉
he translates to
彼はこう訳します
holy
聖なる
And you see a music added to the back
そして後ろに音楽が追加されているのがわかります
In other words what is holy
つまり神聖とは何か
what word
何という言葉
verb
動詞
San Dang verb
サンダン動詞
in Chinese
中国語で
I
私
in the knowledge of some
一部の知識の中で
almost never saw me
ほとんど私に会ったことはありません
saint can be a noun
聖人は名詞になりえます
can make this a new word
これを新しい言葉にすることができます
But in our usage
しかし、私たちの使い方では
At least in the usage of Mandarin
少なくとも北京語の使用においては
It's not a proper verb
それは適切な動詞ではありません
But He Qingtai
しかし、何青台
he takes him as a verb
彼は彼を動詞として捉えている
to use
来用
OK
OK
this is a very special place
ここはとても特別な場所です
There are some words besides
他にもいくつか言葉があります
For example, if there are more than two characters, we call them words.
たとえば、3 つ以上の文字がある場合、それらを単語と呼びます。
OK
OK
Some of the applications used in ancient and modern times
古代と現代で使用されていたアプリケーションのいくつか
some of the more common words
より一般的な単語のいくつか
I put the Guina out for example
たとえばギナを出しました
the total one
合計1つ
total of this word
この単語の合計
This word is our current way of speaking
この言葉が今の私たちの話し方です
Mr. He's teaching is of common species
何先生の教えはありふれたものです
just heard
ちょうど聞いた
OK
OK
I'm going to check Honglianmeng
紅蓮夢をチェックしてみます
I just found out
今ちょうど見つけた
Mr. He did not make a mistake
ミスター彼は間違いを犯しませんでした
Red lotus dream is full of co-species
赤い蓮の夢は同種でいっぱいです
OK
OK
So he did nothing wrong
だから彼は何も間違ったことはしていない
What about the snake?
ヘビはどうですか？
Snake is what we say in Taiwan now
台湾では今、ヘビと言います。
What about Hebei people?
河北省の人はどうですか？
To this day, people in Hebei still hold a
今日に至るまで、河北省の人々は、
snake called snake
蛇という蛇
Let's say again that I have an old minister from Hebei.
もう一度言っておきますが、私には河北省出身の老大臣がいます。
maybe you will understand
おそらくあなたは理解するでしょう
OK
OK
That
それか
help
ヘルプ
they are quite
彼らはかなりです
OK quite
わかりました、かなり
Of course I also feel
もちろん私もそう感じています
Are you so wrong
そんなに間違ってるの？
OK
OK
So luckily there's a lot of this now
幸いなことに、今はこれがたくさんあります
Novel
小説
This one has electronic boards to search
これには検索用の電子ボードがあります
OK
OK
I look down
私は見下ろします
Wow
おお
I have no knowledge myself
私自身知識がありません
not to come in without knowledge
知識なく入ってはいけない
is quite right
全く正しいです
OK
OK
I'm pretty inside
私はかなり内側にいる
one year
一年
when you want to help
手助けしたいとき
it's almost
ほとんどです
Almost all of this uses the word quite
ほぼ全員が「かなり」という言葉を使います
There's this coolness in there
そこにこのクールさがあります
This was originally from the book
これはもともと本から出てきたものです
OK
OK
Kakindai
賀金台
it also uses
それも使用します
OK
OK
Since it came out of the book
本に出てきたから
Actually it doesn't necessarily mean
実は必ずしもそうとは限りません
This non-profit
この非営利団体は、
This Beijinger will only use this one
この北京人はこれしか使いません
I don't know if people in other places will use it
他の地域の人が使うかどうかはわかりません
OK
OK
Then this will actually be something we won't talk about.
そうすれば、これは実際には話さないことになります。
Then if this is taken as
次に、これを次のように解釈すると、
most people in the world
世界中のほとんどの人が
It's back to the previous page.
前のページに戻りました。
Tinnitus Heroes
耳鳴りヒーローズ
or Red European Dream
あるいは赤いヨーロッパの夢
The writing time of Hongoumeng
ホンゴウメンの執筆時間
In fact, it was the pre-agricultural era
実は農耕以前の時代だった
The biography of Wenkang's tinnitus heroes is more difficult to say
文康の耳鳴り英雄の伝記は言うのがさらに難しい
Some people deduce him to these tariffs
一部の人々は彼にこれらの関税を課していると推測する
Someone said to go to Daoguang
誰かが道光に行くと言った
but no matter what
でも何があっても
Many scholars believe
多くの学者は信じています
Tinnitus Heroes should represent
耳鳴りヒーローは代表すべき
Probably from Qiannong to Daoguang
おそらく乾農から道光まで
This is about a hundred years or so
これは百年ほど前のことだ
Beijing dialect in Beijing
北京の北京弁
OK
OK
So I had to choose these novels
だから私はこれらの小説を選ばなければならなかった
To do well is a litmus test
うまくやるということはリトマス試験紙だ
Check out this gold belt
このゴールドベルトをチェックしてください
used some weird words
変な言葉を使った
is it right or wrong
それは正しいですか、間違っていますか
it made me realize
それは私に気づかせてくれた
he did use it
彼はそれを使いました
OK, in other words, these words, in a sense, they should be some words commonly used by ordinary people in Beijing in this century
OK、つまり、これらの言葉は、ある意味、今世紀の北京の庶民がよく使う言葉の一部になるはずだ
OK, let's see the next one
はい、次を見ましょう
From this point of view, we can all say that when He Xingnai is translating, he prefers to use the so-called planning strategy.
この観点から見ると、何星内は翻訳の際に、いわゆる計画戦略を使用することを好むと言えます。
OK, this English is called domestication
OK、この英語は家畜化​​と呼ばれます
Planning means to follow the Chinese teaching method
計画とは中国の教授法に従うことを意味します
OK, but, sometimes this planning is really too planned
OK、でも、この計画は本当に計画的すぎる場合があります
OK, some people like their special panis, this pie
OK、特別なパニ、このパイが好きな人もいます
OK, IOR was in the birth of God, Yanqing fierce, in the early seventeenth century
OK、IORは17世紀初頭、延慶の激しい神の誕生にありました
OK, he is taking this disease, this disease is a layer of disease
OK、彼はこの病気を患っています、この病気は病気の層です
The whole Panis is sick, because it is still called sick, right?
パニス全体が病気なのは、まだ病気と言われているからですよね？
OK, but what about He Jintai, he, super planned
OK、でも何金台はどうですか、彼、とても計画的です
OK, he called it Mantou
OK、彼はそれをマントウと呼んでいました
Ah, what about steamed buns? If you talk about this, he will continue to localize it.
ああ、肉まんはどうですか? この話をすると、どんどんローカライズしてくれます。
He just called him Bobo, OK
彼はただ彼をボボと呼んだ、OK
So he has several kinds of this, this epidemic method, in fact, they are all similar to steamed buns
それで、彼はこれを何種類か持っています、この伝染病の方法、実際、それらはすべて蒸しパンに似ています
OK, what about the ranan pancake that we now make?
さて、これから作るラナンパンケーキはどうでしょうか？
He simply put a layer of pancake, I don't know if pancake has words, OK
彼は単にパンケーキの層を置いただけです、パンケーキに言葉があるかどうかはわかりません、OK
Then he was originally this, this, this, this, this, this so-called Cruce Do, this
それで、彼はもともとこれ、これ、これ、これ、いわゆるクルーセ・ドゥ、これでした。
the word
言葉
It means flat
平らという意味です
it is flat and thin
平らで薄いです
I really don't know what a flat thin thing is
平らで薄いものが何なのか本当に分かりません
Everyone should be more flat-faced steamed buns.
みんなもっと平たいおまんじゅうになればいいのに。
so you're inside the last supper
それであなたは最後の晩餐の中にいます
jesus said
イエスは言いました
Jesus broke the cake
イエスはケーキを割った
Then give his picture say this
それから彼の写真を渡してこう言ってください
This is my body
これが私の体です
this is my body
これは私の体です
What about this paragraph?
この段落はどうでしょうか？
He Jindai wrote it like this
彼神代はこう書いている。
Jesus surrendered to this steamed bun
イエスはこの饅頭に降伏した
Then what
じゃあ何
Divide the buns into pieces
バンズを分割します
good at this his steamed bun
彼の蒸しパンはこれが得意です
OK
OK
where is jesus
イエスはどこですか
he himself
彼が彼自身で
Metaphor yourself as a business
自分自身をビジネスに喩える
these two
この二つ
Doesn't he have Ling Wangtang?
リン・ワンタンはいないのですか？
isn't it
ではない？
OK
OK
Gu Xin's voice
グ・シンの声
Translate the words of Jesus
イエスの言葉を翻訳してください
I am a steamed bun of business
私は営業のおまんじゅうです
OK
OK
i don't know this
これはわかりません
How did Beijingers sound at that time?
当時の北京人の声はどんな感じだったのでしょうか？
but today we
しかし今日私たちは
Woke up today feeling weird
今日起きたら変な気分だった
that's even weirder
それはさらに奇妙です
this hunting king
この狩猟王
on this one
これについて
originally a word called
もともとはと呼ばれる言葉でした
charcoal baked pancakes
炭火で焼いたパンケーキ
OK
OK
He Tiannai in his kings gold
キングゴールドの何天内
Hunting King Ji, his name is Zhongwangjin
済王を狩る、彼は中王進と呼ばれる
It is said to be a steamed bun of a living dragon and mouse
生きた龍とネズミの饅頭と言われています
I can't cook though
料理はできないけど
can't cook
料理ができない
But I know that steamed buns are steamed
でも肉まんは蒸しているのは知っています
He said steamed buns belong to mice
彼は饅頭はネズミのものだと言いました
We also know that this duck's he went
アヒルが行ったことも私たちは知っています
he has many of these
彼はこれらをたくさん持っています
This kind of over-planning
こういう過剰な計画は
this sentence
この文章
find it very interesting
とても面白いと思います
Let's look at the next page
次のページを見てみましょう
OK
OK
Another place to plan is
もう一つ計画する場所は、
this
これ
He Tiannai said that Tiandao
何天内は天島をこう言った。
The physics museum in this origin
物理博物館の原点
go paint
絵を描きに行く
OK
OK
in other words
言い換えると
Qing Palace
清宮
he actually
彼は実際に
not angry
怒っていない
he is not good
他不妙聲的
The language of the Qing court
清の宮廷言語
he is very familiar
彼はとてもよく知っています
So inside the ancient and modern holy palace
古代と現代の聖なる宮殿の内部
There is a Thai
タイ人もいるよ
or the dynasty of the egyptians
あるいはエジプト人の王朝
also often think
もよく考えます
some in here
ここにいくつか
Up and down relationship
上下関係
so
それで
a Guo Wang
郭王
or within a family
あるいは家族内で
richer family
裕福な家族
you see this one
これを見ますか
He Jin people will put the family
何晋の人は家族を置きます
this special character
この特別な文字
called master
マスターと呼ばれる
Those who do things for him are called slaves
彼のために何かをする人は奴隷と呼ばれます
OK
OK
Then what
じゃあ何
master of course
もちろんマスター
Of course the slave must follow the master
もちろん、スレーブはマスターに従わなければなりません
This is commonly known as auspicious
これは一般に縁起の良いものとして知られています
OK
OK
I have to say hello to him too
私も彼に挨拶しなければなりません
so these words
だからこれらの言葉は
you can see that
それがわかります
that is
あれは
He Jin gave birth to a new year's home
何進は新年の家を産んだ
Then his place is indeed
それなら彼の居場所は確かに
also received a public year
パブリックイヤーも受賞
Can't keep up with the impact
衝撃に追いつけない
Not only this effect
この効果だけではなく
There is also the following effect
下記のような効果もあります
we can take a look
見てみましょう
not a good question
良い質問ではありません
there is another
もう一つの...がある
not this
これではない
no and not this
いいえ、これではありません
Just wait until you can't find it
見つからなくなるまで待ってください
we now find
私たちは今見つけました
let me talk
話させてください
ok
Ok
anyway
ともかく
his
他的
his translation strategy
彼の翻訳戦略
basically
基本上
if he can internalize
彼が内面化できれば
or planning
または計画中
he can plan
彼は計画を立てることができる
What I was actually looking for was a
私が実際に探していたのは、
so-called prison
いわゆる刑務所
we just know
私たちはただ知っています
Our green stuff, this growth pack
私たちの環境に優しいもの、この成長パック
see too much
見すぎ
we know what this is
私たちはこれが何であるかを知っています
what diameter
直径は何ですか
Circle diameter is a term that is often heard
円直径とはよく聞く言葉です
In fact, circle diameter is a character of Qingcha
実は円の直径は青茶の形です
There are also various ways of the circle diameter
この円の直径にも色々な方法があります
ok
Ok
if it is
もしそれが
There is a circle of people
人の輪がある
ok
Ok
Foretell this and employ this
これを予告し、これを採用する
you can go no problem
問題なく行けますよ
a little house arrest
ちょっとした自宅軟禁
next to you is a lot of water
あなたの隣にはたくさんの水があります
stand over there
そこに立って
But this line is to monitor you
でもこのラインはあなたを監視するためのものです
ok
Ok
this circle of people
この人の輪
Then there is also this, use strong and low to get angry
それからこれもある、強弱を使って怒る
you ride in it
あなたはそれに乗ります
you are not allowed to run around
走り回ることは許されていません
ok
Ok
some are locked in matter
物質の中に閉じ込められている人もいる
you can't run around
走り回ることはできない
General Su Liyuan seems to be
蘇麗源将軍らしい
experienced these things
これらのことを経験しました
so what
だから何
From this Chinese form, he
この中国語の形から、彼は、
he created himself
彼は自分自身を創造した
egyptians in
エジプト人
sorry
ごめん
some people in egypt this
エジプトの一部の人たちはこれを
quilt
キルト
what
何
means being forced to do something
何かをすることを強制されることを意味します
when writing some projects
いくつかのプロジェクトを書くとき
He invented this engineering circle
彼はこのエンジニアリングサークルを発明しました
ok
Ok
that pair of gold
その金のペア
prison circle
刑務所サークル
He is buying now
彼は今買っています
OK came across these in China
OK、中国でこれを見つけました
this lecture
この講義
Just translate it like this
こう訳すだけです
OK
OK
Well
良い
How to say
どのように言って
Although this is a
これは
this one
これです
Well
良い
Um
えーっと
Compare
比較
close to this China
この中国の近くに
A kind of
のようなもの
translation method
翻訳方法
However, this translation method is already a language
ただし、この翻訳方法はすでに言語です
Well
良い
It's not just translating this language anymore.
もうこの言語を翻訳するだけではありません。
He is also translating culture
彼は文化の翻訳も行っています
OK
OK
Well
良い
so i say
だから私は言います
in here
ここに
Well
良い
cusine bible this one
料理のバイブルこれ
this
これ
when he is thinking
彼が考えているとき
He Jinnai is thinking about this one
陣内はこんなことを考えている
how to translate when
いつどのように翻訳するか
in fact already
実際にはすでに
total
合計
already already
もうすでに
is doing a
をやっている
Well
良い
this one of culture
これは文化の一つ
Transferred this question
この質問を転送しました
OK
OK
what about this question
この質問はどうですか
If this cultural transfer across state lines
この文化が州境を越えて伝わるとしたら
Actually
実際
is what we call modernity today
それが今日私たちが現代と呼ぶものです
this ring
この指輪
OK
OK
I dare not say this ancient and modern scripture
私はあえてこの古今の経典を言いません。
How closely related to what we call modernity
私たちが現代と呼ぶものとどれほど密接に関係しているか
But at least I invented a term called
しかし少なくとも私は という用語を発明しました
dad called
お父さんが電話した
bottom
下
Chen Feng's modernity in what he often said
チェン・フェンがよく言ったことの現代性
i think it should be ok
大丈夫だと思います
OK
OK
I haven't written anything yet
まだ何も書いていない
I spoke
私が話した
We have probably already talked about this bandon
このバンドンについてはおそらくすでに話したでしょう
i think i keep talking
私は話し続けていると思う
because it's almost time
そろそろ時間なので
I have been talking about a He Jintai
何金台の話をしてきました
This ancient and modern scripture
この古今の経典
I once did a study
一度勉強したことがある
is one this one clear one
これは 1 つです
Missionaries called Marlowe
マーロウと呼ばれる宣教師
a novel he wrote
彼が書いた小説
OK
OK
He based this on Cicero's
彼はこれをシセロの作品に基づいています
The Republic
共和国
OK
OK
That Skipio on the last side
最後の方のスキピオ
His housewife took him to heaven
彼の主婦が彼を天国に連れて行った
Then look around the universe from the sky and see the earth
そして空から宇宙を見回して地球を見てください
An imagination of Cicero like this
シセロの想像はこんな感じ
This vision of Joseph Marosell visiting Cicero
ジョセフ・マロセルがキケロを訪問したときの幻視
wrote a novel
小説を書きました
I haven't read this novel.
私はこの小説を読んだことがありません。
I only see superbooks
スーパーブックしか見ない
i have a day
一日あります
once i wrote an article
一度記事を書いたら
when reading at a meeting
会議で本を読むとき
someone asked me
誰かが私に尋ねました
What's the point of your research on superbooks
スーパーブックに関する研究の意味は何ですか
This means that
この意味は
Superbook is just a person
スーパーブックは単なる人間です
copy a book
本をコピーする
It does not mean that the book had a great influence
この本が大きな影響を与えたというわけではない
What is the point of your research on this ultrabook?
このウルトラブックに関する研究のポイントは何ですか?
OK
OK
I know your key is the so-called influence
あなたの鍵がいわゆる影響力であることは知っています
this question
この質問
That Marlowe is another question
マーロウについてはまた別の問題だ
actually
実際
That question is a big one
その質問は大きな質問です
OK Maloser affected financial love
OK マロザーは経済的愛に影響を与えた
OK
OK
Superbook not engraved things
スーパーブックは刻印されていないもの
For later Maloser was a Catholic missionary
後にマロセルはカトリックの宣教師となった
But what?
でも何？
But this one he wrote
しかし、これは彼が書いたものです
This one is not engraved
こちらは刻印されていません
dream no soil skills
夢のない土のスキル
It's a dream of heaven, a dream of heaven
それは天国の夢です、天国の夢です
OK
OK
Meng did not have soil skills, but it affected the later Protestantism
孟には土の技術はなかったが、後のプロテスタントに影響を与えた
Guo Shili
郭詩利
OK
OK
let's say this one
これを言ってみましょう
this one milian
このミリアン
some of their missionary novels
彼らの宣教小説のいくつか
OK
OK
that's full
それはいっぱいです
a terrible thing
ひどいこと
OK
OK
What about He Qingtai?
何清台はどうですか？
He Qingtai This Old and New Bible
何清台この新旧聖書
same
同じ
he is still
彼はまだいます
The first trainer is not allowed to take a tick
最初のトレーナーはティックを取ることはできません
he does not
他不
Don't mess around
めちゃくちゃにしないでください
ok
Ok
The coach doesn't allow Kona to count.
コーチはコナにカウントを許可しなかった。
The coach is not allowed
コーチは許可されていません
The coach has nothing to show others
コーチは他人に見せるものが何もない
ok
Ok
So around the year 181,000
つまり、約 181,000 年
Just a little bit more relaxed Catholicism
もう少しリラックスしたカトリック
catholic or catholic room
カトリックまたはカトリックの部屋
ok
Ok
just take this
これだけ取ってください
He Jintai's ancient nerve
何晋台の古代の神経
The part of the welfare book inside.
中の福祉本の一部。
ok
Ok
take it to guangzhou
広州に持って行きます
show this one
これを見せて
The first Protestant missionary to China
中国初のプロテスタント宣教師
Robert Morrison
ロバート・モリソン
ok Morrison
オーケー、モリソン
So Morrison was
それでモリソンは
read this one
これを読んでください
Well
良い
this one
これです
archaic nerve
古風な神経
at least he read
少なくとも彼は読んだ
welfare book ok
福利書的 ok
but i feel like
でも私はそう感じます
I'm afraid it's not just the welfare book
福祉の本だけではないと思います。
Morrison's category of reading
モリソンの読書カテゴリー
I'm afraid it's pretty big ok
かなり大きいと思いますが、大丈夫です
A bible later said to be the first master translation in China
後に中国初のマスター翻訳と言われた聖書
so-called holy book
いわゆる聖典
In fact, a large part of it was influenced by He Jingtai
実際、その大部分は何敬泰の影響を受けています。
If you have read the sacred book
聖典を読んだことがあるなら
The holy book is really read
聖書は本当に読まれています
You will feel that the whole O mouth has reached the extreme
O口全体が極限に達しているのを感じるでしょう
That kind of O mouth is actually related to He Jingtai
そんなO口は実は何敬泰と関係があるのです。
I think I learned it from He Jingtai
何静台から学んだ気がする
Yihe Jingtai's wish is indeed not as plain as its old counterparts
Yihe Jingtai の願いは、確かに古いものほど単純ではありません。
The old dissimilarity is vernacular
昔の相違点はその言語特有のものである
First, because of the various divine and holy books I just mentioned
まず、先ほど述べたさまざまな神聖な書物のせいで、
Their education level is related
彼らの教育レベルは関係している
So there are various problems that manifest
そのため、さまざまな問題が顕在化します
where to choose from time to time
時々どこを選ぶか
Just to learn the kind of words that are more awkward
もっと厄介な言葉の種類を学ぶためだけに
so where to choose this one
それで、これをどこで選ぶか
Well...
良い...
The god has lost
神様は負けた
uh... or so-called psychological lost
ああ...いわゆる心理的喪失
The rescue was lost, etc.
救助が失われた等。
uh...actually
えー...実は
uh...been through this one
ああ...これを経験したことがある
and mentality of this one influence
そしてこの1つの影響の精神
even with charitable intentions
たとえ慈善的な意図があっても
he's been affected
他的受過影響
It means that we are actually
つまり、私たちは実際に
We actually have two postures in Paradise today
今日、パラダイスでは実際に 2 つの姿勢があります
catchy
キャッチーな
When I was a child there was another called
私が子供の頃、別の名前が付けられていました
Cigarettes of Heart Paradise
ハートパラダイスのシガレッツ
But it's not easy for everyone to see
しかし、誰もがそれを見るのは簡単ではありません
Uh... if you have this mentality
ああ...もしあなたがこの精神を持っているなら
Must be... antique
きっと…アンティーク
must be very valuable
とても貴重なものに違いない
then...we...
それから...私たち...
What about the two poses of Paradise?
パラダイスの2つのポーズはどうでしょうか？
not from china
中国からではない
Only Buddhism can use it
仏教のみが使用できる
The two poses of Paradise
パラダイスの 2 つのポーズ
Is there a paradise in China
中国に楽園はありますか
if you look for it in the world
世界で探したら
That's Leto
それはレトです
Tu Yang's picture
トゥ・ヤンの写真
Letu
レトゥ
inside to get involved
中に参加するために
I don't know
わからない
But he is indeed the whole of Christianity
しかし、彼は確かにキリスト教全体です
That is to say, including Catholicism and Protestantism
つまり、カトリックもプロテスタントも含めて
Christianity
キリスト教
OK
OK
the whole of christianity
キリスト教全体
Maybe there is a Nestorian in it
もしかしたらネストリウス派もいるかもしれない
OK
OK
First
初め
this says
これは言う
Said that now I want to live in Paradise
今は楽園に住みたいと言いました
this place
この場所
he is the first
彼が最初です
OK
OK
Later, the name has been handed down like this.
その後、このように名前が受け継がれています。
Inside Mirror is in when writing his Huayun dictionary
彼の花雲辞書を書くときに Inside Mirror が登場
He also got up with him
彼も一緒に立ち上がった
Puridice is also translated as this paradise
ピュリディスはこの楽園とも訳されます
Clean it up
きれいにしてください
Puridiso is
プリディソは
Puridion
プリディオン
OK
OK
The word "paradise" is true
「楽園」という言葉は本当です
Yang Tianyu's earliest time
楊天宇の初期の頃
In fact, he dare not translate
実際、彼は敢えて翻訳しませんでした
OK
OK
he called it this
彼はそれをこう呼んだ
Yang Tianyu ran to
ヤン・ティエンユーが駆け寄った
go down
降りる
Um
えーっと
maximum
最大
You don't need to find it, it's okay
探さなくても大丈夫ですよ
anyway, yang tingting is paradise
とにかく、陽ティンティンは楽園です
paradise, paradise
楽園、楽園
ok , he uses this
わかりました、彼はこれを使っています
Bala Tisha or something
バラ・ティシャとか
transliteration
音訳
Because he believes that in Chinese culture
なぜなら彼は中国文化において次のように信じているからです。
Not Christianity, Catholicism
キリスト教じゃなくてカトリック
this concept of this paradise
この楽園の概念
So, the transliteration transliterated
つまり、音訳は
ok, transliterated
わかりました、音訳されました
The later Catholicism is the knowledge of Paradise
後のカトリックは楽園の知識である
There are many ways to say this
これにはいろいろな言い方があります
ok because later on for example
わかりました。後で、たとえば
In this deep area of ​​calm
静かなこの奥深いエリアで
In fact, Paradise is divided into
実際、パラダイスは次のように分かれています。
heavenly paradise with
天国の楽園と
earthly paradise
地上の楽園
And City Paradise
そしてシティパラダイス
Paradise on earth is of course biting the present
地上の楽園はもちろん現在を噛む
Yidian Park
宜甸公園
Paradise
パラダイス
That's the place for the Shangdi Group.
それが上地グループの場所です。
ok then they
わかりました、それでは彼らは
It is derived from this book in China
中国のこの本に由来
For example, the saying of heaven
たとえば、天の言葉
OK
OK
So
それで
It's all this paradise on earth
ここはすべて地上の楽園です
this trouble
この悩み
Yang Tianyu called him
楊天宇が彼に電話した
sorry heaven paradise he still calls him
ごめんなさい、天国の楽園、彼はまだ彼を呼んでいます
Araiso
荒磯
OK
OK
earliest time
最も早い時間
Luo Mingjian fought with Lima when they were in the 1580s
ルオ・ミンジャンは1580年代にリマと戦った
Bring Paradise
パラダイスをもたらす
Paradise on earth
地上の楽園
OK
OK
this
これ
Pavaiso
パヴァイソ
Terry
テリー
OK
OK
he moved him into
彼は彼をそこに移した
buddhist country
仏教の国
OK
OK
Buddha
仏
Buddha's country
仏の国
OK
OK
I tell you
私はあなたに言います
This is because your first time
初めてだから
cultural first encounter
文化的な最初の出会い
when this is a new noun
これが新しい名詞の場合
You do have so many
たくさん持っていますね
so big
とても大きく
this
これ
that kind of words
そういう言葉
the kind of struggle above
上記のような闘争
how to translate
翻訳方法
You're really pretty good at finding out
あなたは本当にそれを見つけるのが得意です
an appropriate translation
適切な翻訳
Naga Jinna is great
ナーガ・ジンナは素晴らしい
He calls a certain language a paradise
彼はある言語を楽園と呼ぶ
Paradise down
パラダイスダウン
Well, Xinjiao also went down with Paradise.
さて、新教もパラダイスとともに滅びました。
Old teaching needless to say
言うまでもなく古い教え
Plaster of the Old Church itself has been
古い教会自体の石膏は
must be paradise
楽園に違いない
Heart Teaching from Morrison
モリソン氏からの心の教え
From Morrison to this Guslev
モリソンからこのグスレフまで
It is the so-called national stone power statement
いわゆる国石パワーステートメントです
wait these people are paradise
待ってください、この人たちは天国です
Paradise to our heart Paradise
私たちの心にパラダイスを
still in Paradise
まだ楽園にいる
So if you want to look at it from the words
だから言葉から見たいなら
this ancient and modern bible
この古代と現代の聖書
marison may not have read it from cover to cover
マリソンは最初から最後まで読んでいないかもしれない
But also affected to some extent
しかし、ある程度の影響も受けます
This can be seen
これは見られます
I don't have that much time
そんなに時間がない
Or one of my two essences is looking at each other
あるいは、私の 2 つの本質のうちの 1 つがお互いを見合っている
I think it should be possible to say something more interesting
もっと面白いことが言えればいいと思う
OK
OK
Then let me talk about style at the end
それでは最後にスタイルについてお話しましょう
This style is OK
このスタイルはOKです
There is a very important scholar in the West
西側に非常に重要な学者がいる
Called Erik Albach
エリック・アルバックと呼ばれる
He said
彼は言った
The more vulgar language in it
より下品な言葉が含まれている
more vulgar language
もっと下品な言葉遣い
to write
書く
doesn't mean you can't
できないという意味ではありません
In this rather vulgar concept
このかなり下品な概念で
in this language to create some kind of
この言語で何らかのものを作成するには
sublime
荘厳な
OK
OK
A feeling like spinning tail
尻尾が回るような感覚
Spin Tail is a Westerner
スピンテールは西洋人です
the most beautiful
美最高的
extreme word
極字
OK
OK
Well
良い
I'll be full of an explanation chest
説明チェストでいっぱいになります
words to explain
説明する言葉
i need this
私はこれを必要とする
another hour
もう一時間
OK
OK
Well
良い
i can only say
私はただ言うことができます
From the two examples I quote below
以下に引用する 2 つの例から
OK
OK
is using a very simple
非常にシンプルなものを使用しています
This one is written in Chinese and this one
これは中国語で書かれており、これは
OK
OK
But what?
でも何？
here you read
ここで読んでください
especially if you have to follow
特にそうするつもりなら
If there are words above and below
上下に単語がある場合
you read
あなたが読む
Your feeling is the feeling of chest and stomach
あなたの気持ちは胸とお腹の感覚
OK
OK
Well
良い
first example
最初の例
This is the third entry from Chinese
これは中国人からの 3 番目のエントリーです
Well
良い
inside this
この中に
this came out
これが出た
talking about
について話す
Well
良い
Alias' question
エイリアスの質問
OK
OK
Well
良い
at that time this
その時これ
this god this
この神様、これ
Hear the prophet Alias
預言者エイリアスの言うことを聞いてください
this one is a bit
これはちょっと
when feeling discouraged
落胆しているとき
god this one
神様、これは
he out
彼は出て行った
he is coming
彼が来ている
he appeared
彼は現れた
OK
OK
in the bible
聖書の中で
Well
良い
sorry
ごめん
This He Jin Dali medical method is a burst of landslides and seas after the appearance of God
この何進大理の医学法は、神の出現後の地滑りと海の爆発です。
strong wind and rain
強い風と雨
Then God is not in the wind
そうすれば神は風の中にいない
After this storm
この嵐の後
It's the same as our list
私たちのリストと同じです
That's right
それは正しい
God is not in this cave
この洞窟には神はいない
but then fire
しかしその後発火します
God is still not in this fire
神はまだ火の中におられない
I added a word for him
私は彼に一言加えました
the day after the fire
火後天
Correction
習正
sound of gentle wind
優しい風の音
there is not a word in it
そこには一言も入っていない
this is the kind
これはその種類です
the kind in the article
記事にある種類
Very high injury point Ya sooner or later
非常に高い怪我ポイントや遅かれ早かれ
But the feeling of God you read
でもあなたが読んだ神の気持ちは
is a rather sublime feeling
かなり崇高な感情です
very serious
非常に深刻な
very dangerous sense of god
非常に危険な神の感覚
OK, so the following example is
さて、次の例は次のとおりです
It's Epsalom, which is very famous for this
とても有名なエプサロムです
this son of david
このダビデの息子
Because he felt that this David would not pass the throne to him
このダビデが王位を自分に譲ることはないだろうと彼は感じたからです。
So he rebelled
それで彼は反逆した
Rebellion wins and loses
反乱には勝ち負けがある
When I lost, I was chased by David
負けたらデビッドに追いかけられた
run after
追いかける
Then Epsalom at the end
そして最後はエプサロム
Epsalom rides this lol all by himself
エプサロムはこれに一人で乗ります（笑）
OK, he suddenly met David's soldier
OK、彼は突然デイビッドの兵士に会った
Then this Luo Zi passed through Qiu Yi
そして、この羅子は秋儀を通過しました。
under the tree
木の下で
His hair got caught by a tree... a branch
彼の髪が木に引っかかってしまった…枝に
The one who rides Luozi is wrong
羅子に乗る者は間違っている
OK, I'll pin it up and run ahead
OK、固定して先に走ります
Then, He Junnai translated a sentence
すると、ヘ・ジュンナイが文章を翻訳した。
In fact, this text is not so clever
実際、この文章はそれほど賢明ではありません
but read it
でも読んでください
The Epsilon
イプシロン
that imagery becomes very large
その画像は非常に大きくなります
he said his body
彼は自分の体だと言いました
hanging between heaven and earth
天と地の間にぶら下がっている
ok
Ok
While reading this I suddenly remembered this
これを読んでいて、ふとこんなことを思い出した
such a legal
そのような合法的な
translation is a kind of interpretation
翻訳は一種の解釈です
ok such a legal
わかりました、そのような合法的な
In fact, the unfilial son of Epsilon has been
実は、不孝な息子であるイプシロンは、
translate it as if that
まるでそうであるかのように訳してください
how to say
どのように言って
You don't bow your head like God
あなたは神のように頭を下げません
There is no such thing as Shadan
シャダンなんてものは存在しない
ok
Ok
The imagery is very, very mammoth
画像は非常に巨大です
Then we see that there is nothing great in it
そうすれば、そこには素晴らしいものは何もないことがわかります
this one word this one appears
この一言 これが登場します
so
それで
this Obach
このオーバッハ
he will say ok
彼は大丈夫と言うだろう
even if
もしそれでも
belong
属する
Nic on the third level question
ニックの第 3 レベルの質問
ok
Ok
You can actually create the feeling of the first episode too
第1話の雰囲気を実際に再現することもできます
It's Xuan Wei's feeling
それは玄偉の気持ちです
I give myself these two examples
私はこれら 2 つの例を自分自身に挙げています
I don't think I will mention the others
他については言及しないと思います
Finally, I will report to you again
最後に改めてご報告させていただきます
I have just reported Protestantism
プロテスタントについて報告したところです
Protestantism influenced by the Old and New Bibles
新旧聖書の影響を受けたプロテスタント
Old teaching bibles until the 1960s one night
ある夜、1960 年代までの古い教育聖書
Although they already cared about it in pre-Canadian times
彼らはカナダ以前の時代にすでにそれを気にしていましたが、
But after this ban and so on
しかし、この禁止措置などの後、
They have to be ordered by the Pope to translate
教皇から翻訳を命じられなければならない
So the old school did not finish the translation until the 1960s
したがって、古い学校では 1960 年代まで翻訳が完了しませんでした。
Everyone has followed the translated old teaching
誰もが翻訳された古い教えに従いました
This Chinese version we call Shi Gaoben
これを中国語バージョンのShi Gaobenと呼びます
The author of the Poetry Gaoben is a
詩「ガオベン」の作者は、
a french italian
フランス系イタリア人
I'm sorry, the priest of the Italian Accounting Society is called Lei Yongming
申し訳ありませんが、イタリア会計協会の司祭は雷永明といいます。
OK
OK
Father Lei Yongming
雷永明神父
italian
イタリアの
When he decided to start translating the bible for employment
仕事のために聖書の翻訳を始めようと決めたとき
sorry when the whole bible
聖書全体を読んでごめんなさい
He is very good with a camera
彼はカメラの使い方がとても上手です
a friend
友達
OK
OK
camera at that time
その時のカメラ
Probably a huge camera
たぶん巨大なカメラ
he ran to
彼は走って行きました
Not long after the end of the Anti-Japanese War
抗日戦争が終わって間もない頃
He ran to Beitang in Beijing
彼は北京の北塘まで走った
OK
OK
What are you doing in Beitang?
北塘で何してるの？
He took He Qingtai's manuscript
彼は何清台の原稿を受け取った
take it all out
すべてを取り出して
it took a whole month
まるまる一ヶ月かかった
they used their
彼らは自分たちのものを使った
It must be a very bulky camera
とてもかさばるカメラでしょうね
Kacha Kacha cards one by one
カチャカチャカード 1枚ずつ
Finally shoot it
ついに撃つ
And bite it to this side
そしてこちら側に噛みつきます
This ding on one side
片側のこのへこみ
Ding Thirty Sides
丁三十面
Then Liu Yongming put the thirty side
その後、Liu Yongming が 30 のビッグサイドを置きました
take him to live longer
彼を長生きさせてください
That is to say, go inside his church
つまり、彼の教会の中に入ってください
because he wants to translate nerve
彼は神経を翻訳したいからです
nerves he can drink in for reference
彼は参考までに酒を飲むことができる神経だ
so if you read
それで読んだら
You read the words of this ancient and modern nerve that you drink in
あなたはこの古今の神経の言葉を読んで酒を飲みます。
You will find that the world knows each other
世界はお互いを知っていることがわかるでしょう
Because Liu Yongming has too many nouns
劉永明は名詞が多すぎるので
They are all citing this ancient and modern nerve of drinking Qingtai
彼らは皆、青台酒を飲むという古代と現代の神経について言及しています。
So this nerve that has not been officially published
公式に発表されていないこの神経
it's not without impact
影響がないわけではない
it has a lot of influence
それは大きな影響力を持っています
Both the Heart Teaching and the Old Teaching both influence
心の教えと古い教えの両方が影響を与えます
For those of us who are generally non-religious
普段無宗教である私たちにとって
We also often hang some, such as saints
聖人などを吊るすこともよくあります。
These names, the names on these religions
これらの名前、これらの宗教の名前
etc
等
I still want to tell you
まだ伝えたい
What about these nouns?
これらの名詞はどうでしょうか？
OK
OK
Then because of this one of the old and new religions
そして、これが古くて新しい宗教の一つであるため、
especially Protestant
特にプロテスタント
Uh, use the past
ああ、過去を使ってください
OK and then it becomes as if
OK、そして次のようになります
S-A-I-N-T
聖人
Sent
送信済
as if it becomes
まるでそうなるかのように
uh bible uh sorry
ああ、聖書、ああ、ごめんなさい
There is a fixed one in the dictionary
辞書には決まったものがあります
One way to explain it is
それを説明する一つの方法は、
S-A-I-N-T
聖人
saint
聖徒
OK it becomes like this
OK、こうなります
OK
OK
uh i spend a lot of time
ああ、私は多くの時間を費やしています
uh 150
えー、150
This one of 1.5 million words
これは 150 万語のうちの 1 つです
uh this one this one
ああ、これはこれ
Such a big book OK
こんな大きな本でもOK
uh i see
ああ、なるほど
uh gave this one for 150 days
ああ、これを150日間与えた
Maybe I'm just talking about this one
もしかしたらこれについて話しているだけかも知れません
able to speak
話せる
be clearer
もっと明確に
OK so today
はい、それでは今日
uh actually
えー、実は
obviously keep one
明らかに1つ持っておいてください
uh talk a little bit
ああ、少し話してください
I just hope this one is right
これが正しいことを願うばかりです
everybody this one
みんなこれ
Whether it is language history or
言語史にしても、
OK Shenjing translation is also good
OK沈京翻訳もいいですね
OK even linguistics
語学でもOK
OK
OK
Let alone this comparative literature
この比較文献はもちろんのこと、
Or in terms of teaching
あるいは教育面でも
The contribution of this book is actually quite large.
実は本書の貢献は非常に大きい。
It is very worthwhile for us to study
私たちにとって勉強するのはとても価値のあることです
ok thank you all
わかりました、皆さんありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you Professor Li Shixue
李世雪先生、ありがとうございました
we'll take ten minutes
10分ほどかかります
So there are probably only three or four questions
質問は 3 つか 4 つかもしれません
keep it short please
短くしてください
Thank you Professor Li for your wonderful speech
李先生、素晴らしい講演をありがとうございました
what i want to ask is
私が聞きたいのは
a little bit of me
私のことを少し
Of course I understand the content
もちろん内容は理解しています
i have a doubt
私は疑問を持っています
That is to say, he was in Beijing
つまり彼は北京にいました
I believe he should be able to see
彼には見えるはずだと私は信じている
For the first time, most people can't read
初めて、ほとんどの人が読めなくなる
The second time I'm sure he'll notice too
二度目は彼が気づくべきだったと思う
In fact, the life of ordinary people
実際、普通の人々の生活は、
Although the Forty-Five Classics are written in classical Chinese
古典四十五は漢文で書かれていますが、
but everyone will
でも誰もがそうするだろう
can also read and sing
読んだり歌ったりすることもできる
even
平
Another one is to say
もう一つはこう言うことです
Even if you are a small person with four classics
たとえあなたが小さな人でも4つの古典を持っています
at formal gatherings
正式な集まりで
Classical Chinese is often used
古典中国語がよく使われます
Then he observed these conditions
それから彼はこれらの状況を観察しました
why did you decide to say
なぜ言うことにしたのですか
He must use such straightforward language
彼はそのような率直な言葉を使わなければなりません
come and translate his bible
来て彼の聖書を翻訳してください
did he respond to this
彼はこれに答えましたか
He may have observed classical Chinese in
彼は古典的な中国語を観察した可能性があります
comment on the prevailing situation in Chinese society
中国社会の一般的な状況についてのコメント
this first
これを最初に
then again that is to say
それからまた、つまり
Did he see some
彼は何かを見ましたか
Chinese vernacular
中国語の言葉
vernacular-like text
日常的なテキスト
pretty passable
還蠻通行
Quite able to call people
人に電話をかけるのがかなり上手
That's why he translated his bible like this
だからこそ彼は聖書をこのように翻訳したのです
Thanks
ありがとう
this is a very good question
これはとても良い質問です
let me this take me just this
これだけ持って行かせてください
In fact, what should be said is
実際に言うべきことは、
guest in this world
この世界のゲスト
I really can't speak
本当に話せないんです
In fact, we have always had an idea
実際、私たちは常にアイデアを持っていました
thought that this jesus would
このイエスならそうなると思った
came to China
中国に来た
Only learning this classical Chinese can lead to upward development
この古典中国語を学ぶだけで上達することができます
That is to say
つまり
In the past, the development of the husband class was preached
かつては夫層の発展が説かれた
OK
OK
That
それか
it's a big one
それは大きいです
at least in percent of this
少なくともこのうちの何パーセントかは
forty to fifty percent above
40～50パーセント以上
This is a mistake
これは間違いです
OK
OK
The Jesuits certainly wrote a lot of literary books
イエズス会士は確かに多くの文学本を書きました
But throughout the Jesuit tradition
しかし、イエズス会の伝統全体を通して
There are also many books written in vernacular
現地語で書かれた本もたくさんあります
also a lot
もたくさん
And there are many of these books
そして、こういった本はたくさんあります
Because of the understanding of the Chinese
中国人の理解力があるので、
It's actually beautifully written
実に綺麗に書かれていますね
Vernacular Novels of the Ming and Qing Dynasties
明清時代の郷土小説
is avoidable
回避可能です
I think He Jinnai
ヘ・ジンナイだと思います
The first one, of course he was influenced by luck
最初のものは、もちろん運に影響されました
The second one I can't quite agree with.
2番目については、私はまったく同意できません。
What you just said was in the pre-Canadian era
あなたが今言ったことはカナダ以前の時代のことです
Classical Chinese seems to be a dominant language
古典中国語が主流の言語のようです
a bully language
いじめっ子の言語
what i was actually trying to say was
私が実際に言おうとしていたのは
I think that in the general middle and lower society of the pre-Canadian era
カナダ以前の一般的な中下層社会では、
The real language of power is vernacular
権力の本当の言語は現地語である
OK is vernacular
OK は現地語です
I can't only
できない
I don't mean this vernacular novel
この俗小説のことを言っているわけではありません
this kind of popular fiction and stuff like that
この種の人気小説やそのようなもの
I mean, let's say
つまり、言ってみましょう
The Victory News
勝利のニュース
OK, Shengli Guangxun
OK,勝利廣訊
Well, Shengli Guangxun, to be honest, this
まあ、勝利光勲、正直に言うと、これは
The original, the original thing
オリジナル、オリジナルのもの
If you haven't passed by Wang Youpu
王友浦を通り過ぎていない場合
Wang Youpu is a disciple of this Fangbao
王有プーはこの方宝の弟子です
OK, without Wang Youpu
はい、王友浦を経由しませんでした
He rewrote it into vernacular
彼はそれを俗語に書き直した
OK, there is another person
はい、別の人がいます
There are two very popular books in total
大好評の2冊です
This one of Shengli Guangxun, they are called Guangxun Xie
これは勝利光勲の一人で、彼らは謝光勲と呼ばれています。
explain it, ok
説明してください、わかりました
It's all vernacular, OK
それはすべて俗語です、OK
The vernacular writing is also really good, OK
現地語の文章もとても良いです、OK
Without these, without these two vernacular texts
これらがなければ、これら 2 つの現地語のテキストがなければ
That's especially Guangxunjie
それは特に光勲街です
It's Wang Youpu's book, OK
王友浦の本ですよ、わかりました。
I doubt this victory
この勝利には疑問がある
this victory, ok
この勝利、よし
this victory, he
この勝利、彼は
To what extent can it penetrate into the hearts of the people?
それはどこまで人々の心に浸透するのでしょうか？
The in-depth broadcast is
徹底した放送は、
Make this Morison very
このモリソンをとても大切にしてください
Influence Morison
影響Morison
deeply affected
影響得非常深
Morison would love to say
モリソン氏はこう言いたい
I will use this text from Guangxun to translate
Guangxun からのこのテキストを使用して翻訳させてください
OK
OK
just it later this
この後だけ
it came after this
この後に来た
Superstitious about this one again
これについてまた迷信深い
have to use
非得用
not document
文書ではない
That means
つまり、
Thai is not good either
タイ語もダメ
Taibai is not good either
タイバイもダメだ
So it ends up taking
それで結局かかります
subtext
サブテキスト
OK
OK
this subject matter
この主題
Let's translate this sacred book
この神聖な本を翻訳しましょう
The subtext is written in the handwriting of foreigners
字幕は外国人の手書きです
In fact, there will be no white
実際には白は存在しません
The kind of taste that the good country interprets
良い国が解釈する味
OK
OK
so
それで
The sacred book becomes one
聖なる書はひとつになる
it's a mouthful to read
読むのは一口です
one book
一本書
OK
OK
I actually think this
実はこう思うんです
Well
良い
rely on that
それによって
He was affected by this dream of Jiu Zun
彼はJiu Zunのこの夢に影響を受けました
In fact, the success of Wang Yepu's Guangxun Festival
実際、王葉浦の光勲祭の成功は、
Also one, although he didn't make it clear
彼は明確にしなかったが、それもその1つである
At least it was the prevailing social situation at that time
少なくとも当時の社会情勢はそうでした
he sees clearly
彼ははっきりと見えます
because he can't follow
彼はフォローできないから
because going to politics he
彼は政界に行くから
socialize with the upper class
上流階級と交流する
OK
OK
you can't date seven years
7年も付き合えないよ
you can't associate with nobles
貴族とは付き合えない
you want to date
デートしたいですか
Then go to even give him this one special one fate
それから彼にこの特別な運命を与えに行ってください
scheduled to say
言う予定の
You don't preach to the one above
あなたは上の人に説教をしません
OK
OK
You have to explain this Catholic truth to this world-class man
あなたはこの世界一流の男にこのカトリックの真実を説明しなければなりません
nothing too big a problem with this
これに関しては特に大きな問題はありません
OK
OK
i want these
これらが欲しいです
Of course it all contributed to why he
もちろん、それはすべて彼がなぜ
in an era of pre-dragons
ドラゴン以前の時代に
He decided to use this vernacular
彼はこの言葉を使うことに決めた
to translate
翻訳すること
OK
OK
Then I'll look at dating as a whole
次に、デート全体を見ていきます
Probably this era of Limadou
おそらくこのリマドゥの時代
Limadou itself already uses the vernacular
リマドゥ自体はすでに現地語を使用しています
preaching to this lower class
この下層階級に説教する
This is his more
これが彼のさらなるものです
More time is spent with the upper layer
上位層でより多くの時間が費やされる
So he also wrote that Catechism
そこで彼は次のようにも書きました。
Q&A on transactions
お取引に関するQ&A
he wrote in vernacular
彼は現地語で書いた
Then you probably from this
それからあなたはおそらくこれから
That's about 1605 or so.
それは1605年くらいのことです。
that book was engraved
その本には刻まれていた
you can look all the way down
ずっと下まで見ることができます
Seeing He Qingdai's era
何清台の時代を見て
that jesus book written in vernacular
現地語で書かれたイエスの本
There are more than fifty or sixty kinds
50～60種類以上あります
OK
OK
If you want to search harder
さらに詳しく検索したい場合は
Maybe there are more than fifty or sixty kinds
もしかしたら50～60種類以上あるかもしれない
OK
OK
i say the whole thing
私はすべてを言います
He Qingdai is the fifty or sixty kinds
何青台は50か60種類です
Or perhaps not only the fifty
あるいは50人だけではないかもしれない
some things we just can't see
私たちには見えないものもあります
OK
OK
not yet visible
まだ見えません
He wrote in these vernacular
彼はこれらの言葉で書きました
top performer
トップパフォーマー
he wrote the most
彼が一番たくさん書いた
most intentional
他意的最多
And what?
そして何？
very very
非常非常
Interestingly
興味深いことに
This he is not like this traditional novel
彼はこの伝統的な小説とは違います
ok
Ok
What about traditional novels?
伝統的な小説はどうですか
vernacular novels have their fixed
現地の小説には固定されたものがある
rhythm of speech
話し方のリズム
ok
Ok
this rhythm of writing
この執筆リズム
He Jinnai doesn't have this set at all
陣内はこのセットを全く持っていない
the way he speaks
彼の話し方
he writes articles
彼は記事を書きます
sorry for the way this bible was translated
この聖書の翻訳方法を残念に思います
like the way we write today
今日の私たちの書き方のように
We are actually speaking here today including me
今日は私も含めて実際にここで話しています
In fact, we all use the European topic
実際、私たちは皆、ヨーロッパの話題を使います。
speaking
話し中
ok
Ok
us
私たち
not with the traditional
伝統的なものではなく
Well
良い
Let's say this one
これを言ってみましょう
The language in Western Europe
西ヨーロッパのこの言語
Or the language in Hongaomeng
またはホンガオメンの言語
speaking
話し中
ok
Ok
that language instant
その言語のインスタント
There is no way in the true biography
本当の伝記には方法がない
ok
Ok
This article we
この記事では、
Because there's going to be a rush to act
急いで行動することになるから
OK
OK
Hello, thanks
こんにちは、ありがとう
Thank you for the most extraordinary speech
最も素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
I actually have a question
実は質問があるのですが
that is
あれは
You said He Qingtai's vernacular nerves
何青台のその土地の神経だと言ったね
In fact, it affects the later
実はそれが後々に影響するんです
That version of Loberto Morrison's
ロベルト・モリソンのあのバージョン
to my limited knowledge
私の限られた知識では
I know Lobberto Morrison
ロベルト・モリソンを知っています
When he started to prevent the epidemic
彼が疫病の予防を始めたとき
he went to london
彼はロンドンに行きました
Went to the British Museum
大英博物館に行ってきました
copied one
コピーしたもの
I don't know where it came from a nerve
どこから神経が来ているのか分かりません
Then take him as the first book
それから彼を最初の本として取り上げます
Then I met another person in Guangzhou
それから私は広州で別の人に会いました
A nerve gifted to him
彼に与えられた神経
that's what you said
それはあなたが言ったことです
It may be the version of He Qingtai mentioned
それは言及された何清台のバージョンかもしれません
But they are generally
しかし、それらは一般的には
It is still mainly in accordance with the
それは依然として主に次のとおりです。
The version in the British Museum
大英博物館にあるバージョン
I think
私が思うに
I'd like to hear more from you about the ins and outs of this
この件について詳しくお聞きしたいのですが
Thanks
ありがとう
I certainly thought this one was supposed to be adapted to the right
確かにこれは右に適応されるべきだと思いました
The impact on Doctor Cat should be a bit heavier
ドクターキャットへの影響はもう少し大きいはず
because history says so
歴史がそう言っているから
That's what many people say
それは多くの人が言うことです
But when the text on the right
しかし、右側のテキストが
There is no editor like this horse medical news
この馬医療ニュースのような編集者はいない
you are so editing my words
あなたは私の言葉をとても編集しています
That's He Jintai
それは何金泰です
He Jintai, he wants to Wen Baijiazai
何金台、彼は温白家宰を望んでいます
He can't have a gentle relationship
彼は優しい関係を築くことができない
ok
Ok
He was also very uncouth when he was gentle with Bai’s family. This Chinese
白さんの家族に優しい彼も、とても野暮ったかった。
Not like vernacular, not like Wenyuan
現地語とも文源とも違う
ok
Ok
That's how Doctor Cat is translating
ドクター・キャットはこう翻訳している
Well
良い
this so
これで
I certainly can't say that this is a cat doctor
確かにこれは猫医者とは言えません
Didn't receive this impact on the right side of this one
これの右側ではこの衝撃を受けませんでした
I'm afraid that Dr. Cat's influence on the right side is quite big.
右サイドのキャット博士の影響はかなり大きいのではないかと思います。
ok
Ok
But what?
でも何？
He Jintai's stock gold body is also standing in front of Dr. Cat
ヘ・ジンタイのストックゴールドボディもドクター・キャットの前に立っている
Because when Doctor Cat translated the Bible himself
なぜなら、ドクター・キャットが自分で聖書を翻訳したときからです。
He himself listed several of his reference books
彼自身もいくつかの参考図書をリストアップしました
The "Old and New Bible" is in this grade
「新旧聖書」はこの学年です
OK
OK
so i dare not say this one
だからあえてこれは言いません
His influence
他影響力
The influence of the ancient and new bibles is so great that this one is bigger than the forty-one and two sides
新旧の聖書の影響は非常に大きく、この聖書は四十一面二面よりも大きいです。
But it has an effect on the cat doctor
しかし、それはドクター・キャットに影響を与えます。
At least my research so far
少なくとも私のこれまでの研究では
as far as i know
私の知る限りでは
Let's compare their writing styles
彼らの文体を比較してみましょう
Perhaps it can be seen that Doctor Cat is more
おそらくドクター・キャットのほうが優れていることがわかるでしょう。
The 412 side of Pro is still more inclined
Proの412側はさらに傾いています
the old new bible
古くて新しい聖書
OK
OK
that takes a lot of time
それはとても時間がかかります
OK thank you
わかりました、ありがとう
I think we are very thankful for this Christmas today
今日はクリスマスをとても感謝していると思います
I heard Li Sixue called
Li Sixue が電話しているのが聞こえました
It turned into He Qingtai
何清台になった
Made a very in-depth and wonderful program
とても内容の濃い素晴らしいプログラムを作っていただきました
thank you
ありがとう